Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): Michael Tracy, the guy who thinks Israel has nothing to do with the Iran war and he thinks that Jeffrey Epstein was railroaded by the United States justice system.
Do
Speaker 2: you recall Trump in 2024 bragging that he's the most pro-Israel president of all time?
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Well, yeah, is it not relevant that Netanyahu flew to Mar-a-Lago over Christmas, then
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): all of a sudden the Iran crisis started right then and there? I think the Epstein stuff is relevant. Kurt, you're speculating that Epstein
Speaker 5: might be associated with this?
Speaker 5: Yes. That's not what...
Speaker 7: Negotiation. Just like when he... That's not what you don't say! When you vote third party, it implies agnosticism about
Speaker 8: who wins the election. That you think both sides are just as bad. Not necessarily. Okay,
so I
Speaker 8: find that annoying. What
Speaker 9: does J.D. Vance do like a little sycophant that he is? He goes to the cabinet meeting last week with Trump, which is like Kim Jong-un
basically,
Speaker 10: requiring everybody to kiss his ass. And J.D. Vance is no problem with that.
Speaker 10: concerned about israel
Speaker 11: you're better off with the democratic coalition at this point joe rogan had donald trump basically the eve of the presidential election in his studio for three hours he could have asked something about iran it was an ass kiss fest
Speaker 12: dave smith dave smith i'm not crediting dave smith for anything anymore but amazingly i don't think i've heard him say a single thing that's funny he said it would be
Speaker 13: justifiable for me to be murdered because he doesn't like my views on the jeffrey epstein story
All
Speaker 14: right. Welcome, everyone, to the podcast here today. I'm glad to be joined by Kurt Mills, Executive
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): Director of the American Conservative, and Michael Tracy, Independent Journalist on Substack and now
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): collaborating with matt taibbi on his substack they're doing a lot of podcasts together which is cool uh one time contributor
Speaker 16: to the american conservative as well don't forget that in a
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): different era
Speaker 17: politically okay cool well thanks uh both of
you for
Speaker 17: joining no problem
um
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): i'll just preface this by saying uh michael i've been following your work over the years and i've i really respect
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): your ability to punch both sides and uh michael i will say you
have a
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): very unusual
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): um
of i
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): guess philosophy on these things of like you're just willing to just call out anyone including like friends or like people who've had you on their shows or like most people don't go that far most people are like okay i've been on this guy's podcast let's you know but you're you just kind of go for everyone which is a very interesting approach i guess it probably leads to like less big podcast invites but it does it is interesting to see that you're just going to call whatever you see i don't
Speaker 19: i never thought to myself gee i should
Go
Speaker 19: around
Speaker 2: courting podcast invites. I think I'd rather jump off a bridge than do that. But yeah, you're
Speaker 16: right. The media is basically like a big high school click where now like
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): being invited to sit at the lunch table is akin to being invited on some dopey podcast.
And I
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): guess I never made a deliberate
Speaker 21: choice to forego that whole situation.
Speaker 21: perverse social dynamic but i think you're right in observing that that seems to be very
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): commonplace on
you know
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): in fact sam harris tried to do that thing with
me as
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): though i was going to be really offended that i hadn't been invited on his podcast to talk about the epstein case and
that made
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): me unserious and i have to go nibble on my turkey sandwich in the corner so it's yeah it's it's a it's a it's a it's a totally corrosive
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): dynamic i think and it's gotten even worse because
Speaker 24: everybody and their mother has
a podcast
Speaker 24: of course i think we should just abolish all podcasts frankly yeah
Speaker 25: well um
the sam harris
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): thing i was actually going to mention briefly but
like for
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): example like you've you know you've been platformed by tucker in the past on fox news and you know he's out on people like yourself and glenn greenwald and lee fong and all these people um you have like decided to criticize Tucker very aggressively as opposed
to
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): to maintain a level of friendliness that you guys seem to have with you going on his show and obviously getting a wide exposure to his audience. Yeah, I always
Speaker 26: liked him personally. I always got along well with
Speaker 27: him. I appreciated being
given the
Speaker 27: opportunity to go on his top-rated
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): primetime cable news show when he still had that at Fox. Frankly, I kind of yearned for the days where he had a bit more, let's say, guardrails, which...
for
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): better or worse existed on in some form on on fox but um you know i the whole trajectory
Speaker 27: he's had in the past couple a couple years i've definitely been highly wary of but like i'm not a total dick socially you know r word so i i try to maintain some comedy
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): and
With
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): people within reason, but then when he started obfuscating the Iran war origins on behalf of Donald Trump, whom he still professes to, quote, love so much and feel this personal allegiance to, then I thought it became untenable to withhold public interest or criticisms that are squarely in the public interest just out of
some influence.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): misguided notion of social uh propriety but i'm you know i would still i would still chat friendly friendly with him uh today if he were willing to i'm not sure if he would but what are you gonna
do yeah and kurt i
Speaker 14: hope you don't mind just for a couple minutes actually i wanted to ask michael about this before we jump into the debate um but so like michael like would some people that they're more
of the
Speaker 14: mindset of like and i don't know what your the extent of your i'm sort of curious what kurt's
Speaker 30: philosophy is on this yeah
Speaker 14: yeah but before we get to that like some people and i don't know if you were,
if you would, if you
Speaker 14: would say you were friends with Tucker or you had a
Speaker 14: communication but a lot of people when they disagree with others in public they they feel like the social the social ethic is to then reach
Speaker 31: out privately and tell them like hey i don't agree with this before i don't know what your stance on i mean
Speaker 2: i did that i did that over the summer when he had on this daryl cooper character for three
Speaker 16: hours to ramble about epstein and virtually every sentence that came out of this guy's mouth just contained blatant falsehoods that were stoking up this ridiculous frenzy
Speaker 16: and the video or the podcast got millions upon millions of views.
And I was
Speaker 16: being beckoned to address Daryl Cooper as though he was going to prove me decisively wrong about Epstein because I take a little bit more of a contrary perspective, let's say, on that whole story.
And I
Speaker 16: finally sit down and do it, and it was just a total journalistic disservice for Tucker to not just co-platform him. I don't care about platforming anybody per se. It was just the...
Speaker 16: unwarranted authority that was ascribed to this guy as the internet's leading epstein expert supposedly when he
was just
Speaker 16: totally ridiculous i mean and not just ridiculous factually which he was and like you know making up quotes from a federal judge for instance but also that he was being imbued with this uh journalistic authority of sorts by way of tucker and then given access to
Speaker 21: this giant um audience and you know tucker was you know he we've
Speaker 21: We're on good enough terms where he seemed like initially amenable to my queries,
but then it just
Speaker 21: kind of ran up against the brick wall because I think unfortunately, and I say that sincerely because I genuinely like Tucker. Unfortunately, he's been in this epistemic free fall where, you know,
You
Speaker 21: know, just Israel, Epstein, pedophiles, Pizzagate, blah, blah, blah, you know, blinking over and over again. And he just like follows the rabbit
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): and you can't really rein him in. So like the engagement that I attempted with him did not really bear much fruit. But yeah, I mean, I think it's good practice if you know somebody on a personal level to, you know, not just like capriciously go around denouncing them in public if like there may be something that you can sort out privately. But I also think that journalists in particular
Speaker 21: have an obligation
Speaker 32: to,
you know,
Speaker 21: identify when there's a matter of public concern
Speaker 16: and that if addressing the public concern is something that they deem to be in the public interest, then they are obliged to do so within reason. So we're not just influencers. We're not content creators. We're not failed comedians who have a podcast.
Speaker 33: There should be, anyway, ideally, an extra layer of public-spirited obligation that I think is attended to journalists that
Speaker 16: sometimes, yes, does have to supplant the cordialities of just interpersonal dynamics, especially with a person like Tucker who has huge political influence. He's not just like my friend from high school. I mean, I have like five or so friends who I wouldn't do that to...
Speaker 21: most of whom are going to be from high school or from a personal... I didn't meet Tucker through Little League baseball practice. I met him through
a
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): political media arrangement.
Speaker 14: Yeah, so you mentioned all the Epstein stuff,
which I
Speaker 14: still don't really have a strong opinion on that. I've seen your commentary. I've seen you, your friend Glenn Greenwald. He disagrees with you on this as well. And there's Whitney Webb's on one end, and then there's other people, all kinds of takes. I don't really have an informed view on that yet. One last thing I'll just say before we get to the debate,
the Sam
Speaker 14: Harris thing that you mentioned, Michael.
Speaker 14: So Sam, I actually saw that podcast with Coleman. So he basically, if I remember correctly, he insinuated that there might be some ulterior motive to why you're covering Epstein the way you
Speaker 34: are.
I
Speaker 33: gave him enough of a benefit of the doubt when I heard that, that I thought he was somehow trying to intimate that he assumed that I was...
Speaker 33: pro-Trump, or that I
Speaker 21: was anti-anti-Trump in the first term, maybe when he became aware of me, and therefore I was
Speaker 16: taking this perspective on the Epstein issue solely to just exonerate Trump for some kind of crude political reason. But then, you know, I guess I should have been a little bit more cynical, because lots of people then
Speaker 16: informed me that what he probably meant that is I'm actually personally a pedophile or have personal sexual depravities that I'm just like projecting. So I'm
a
Speaker 33: pedophile secretly, but I decided to get really involved in the Epstein story of all stories,
what to
Speaker 33: keep the heat off
me. So I
Speaker 21: don't know, Sam Harris's esteem for his
impeccable logic,
Speaker 21: but I'm not sure that really adds up, which is why he didn't spell out what his qualm was against me.
he just
Speaker 21: kind of alluded to
Speaker 35: something anyway yeah i want to i'd like to i'm sure it's sort of curious about uh before we get to the
Speaker 34: yeah yeah well yeah kurt's take on like this podcast
Speaker 14: social dynamic yeah but i will just say on the sam piece i it is interesting um i would like him to spell out what exactly he meant there because i was confused
but i
Speaker 14: will say uh i'll give a
Speaker 36: two-hour lecture on it i'm sure
Speaker 14: michael you and sam would
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): actually agree on on podcasts to sound like sam goes on and
on about
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, I know. I know as you podcast, you guys are. I read the end of faith
Speaker 37: when I was like 18. So I'm pretty much familiar with Tim Harris. Yes. You're
Speaker 38: a fan of his other stuff.
I'm not
Speaker 39: really a fan of much, but I read it. Okay.
But you
Speaker 14: guys are
in a
Speaker 14: hundred percent agreement. I just want to point that out on the independent media stuff. So
that is
Speaker 31: interesting.
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): I'm not sure if we are really, because he just then did the very thing that he denounced by like doing these
Speaker 41: speculative innuendos that he castigated podcasters for being so eager to do. So I'm not sure we really would agree.
Speaker 14: All right, Kurt, thanks for being patient there. I think Michael is
Speaker 42: curious about your stance on any of this before we get into the
topics of
Speaker 42: the debate. What is the question?
Michael, what are
Speaker 27: you curious about? I just like the social dynamics of journalism where you don't want to offend anybody's sensibilities because
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): you want to get an invite on their podcast or you want to maintain these relationships or something, and therefore you kind of
Speaker 37: swell stuff that you might otherwise be inclined to say that has some public interest...
I'm not
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): offended by the way that you roll. I think it would be different
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): if you were like evangelizing it and saying that people who have different strategies or tactics are immoral or something like that. And then I think the thing that really does bother me, and I won't name people, but people who have a persona personality.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): like on screen or on television or on twitter or whatever on x and then pretend like oh it's just a game behind you know like so like i just think lying is bad and um that's that's kind of my my
uh you know
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): i mean i mean i'm sure within my world i'm considered highly disagreeable compared to michael tracy i'm i'm not so um you're an angel
yeah
Speaker 45: i mean so i i don't i mean
Speaker 46: i admit i have a unusual temperament so i
Speaker 45: don't but
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): i don't really get what the uh i mean i can't imagine anyone honestly wouldn't have michael on because of the way michael rolls you know i think there's people that
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): wouldn't have him on at this point um
i don't know if you
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): want to name names but i mean some of the people michael you've criticized i don't know if they would i would
Speaker 16: imagine tucker probably would not at this point
which
Speaker 16: is fine like that's his prerogative again i'm not you know jockeying to get on any particular podcast i know that's what people seem to
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): do a lot these days
but i
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): don't like i have enough to
do day
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): to day that i'm not like fishing
for some
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): podcast invite but anyway i just
Speaker 21: think there's a
lot of
Speaker 21: sort of subtle corruptions in the current media environment that aren't like well theorized enough but anyway
anything
Speaker 48: else it sort of plays into the theme we're going to be discussing more
Speaker 47: so anything else you want to say on this kurt before we maybe it would be better to just discuss the subject yeah let's get let's dive
Speaker 50: in between our our spirits will be uh
will be
Speaker 50: flushed out and obvious yeah okay so
Speaker 51: uh i we got into some some other stuff there but uh i did want to say both you guys so the the
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): topics of debate today are first of all um what role israel has if any in trump deciding to wage war against
your
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): Iran and then second part of the debate is is MAGA really anti-war or anti-interventionalist and you so you guys both I've enjoyed your commentary and learned a lot and it appears you guys disagree on on these questions but I'm curious
to see
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): how much you would disagree if at all
Speaker 55: debate
Is
Speaker 55: this a debate? Opening statements?
No,
Speaker 54: I always do more
Speaker 55: conversational debates. I'll give an
Speaker 49: opening statement if you'd like. I'll stand on my podium.
Speaker 56: You're not Max Abrams, so I'll allow it. Max Abrams,
Speaker 57: that's a piece of work. He hasn't spoken to me since October 7th.
He's bad
Speaker 57: faith.
We got
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): along. Interesting. I mean, he's another guy. I mean, we got along reasonably well. I mean, I wasn't really friends with him, but then he decided that I was like
Speaker 49: persona non grata because I thought some of the anti-Semitism hysteria was kind of overstated after October 7th, but that was enough to get me banished.
Hmm.
Speaker 58 (lower-pitched voice): So, OK, so before we get into it, so just my sense of both you guys, Kurt,
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): you've been very much criticizing Israel and their role in American
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): politics and this decision that Trump made to wage war. And then, Michael, you know, you're it's interesting how you've just morphed in the independent media landscape and like kind of like occupy not substantively, but just.
the
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): issues that you like there's a limited amount of time in the day you can only focus on so many issues and it's interesting like some of the issues that you focus on that that then makes people think of you in a certain way versus when you were talking about other issues but lately you've been very um critical of people attributing uh i think in your view excessive weight on israel's influence in recent political decisions um so you want me to just
Speaker 60: explain um
Speaker 60: I'll
Speaker 21: give like I'll give like a minute of an explanation. OK, so number one, I have been critical from the moment that I entered the public arena,
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): let's say, in
a media
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): or journalistic capacity of the influence of Israel on U.S. foreign policy and how there used to be anyway a taboo against honestly appraising that.
But now I now
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): there's been a strange overcorrection.
Speaker 16: Where.
This
Speaker 16: sort of like metaphysical primacy is constantly attributed to Israel that plays a convenient political role or has a convenient political function for certain people who I would argue presented a fun house mirror version of Trump.
as
Speaker 16: aligned with their proclivities on, say, non-interventionism or realism or whatever synonym you want to use, that culminated with the 2024 election where the podcast audiences, anti-establishment podcast audiences, thought that they were voting for somebody who was going to storm into office with an Avengers squad of RFK Jr. and Tulsi Gabbard and Joe Rogan and Elon Musk and defeat the deep state, release the Epstein files, and
Speaker 33: end the wars. That was just a nonsense cartoon.
Speaker 33: that was effective propaganda. Oh,
Speaker 61: yeah. Yeah,
it was
Speaker 33: effective propaganda. I've always acknowledged
Speaker 21: that. And Kamala Harris certainly couldn't match it. But it was just totally inane and totally divorced from
Speaker 16: Trump's record, his rhetoric, his personnel, and what could be deciphered of his ideology. So I sort of bemoan it from that perspective. So what you have people of that inclination now doing, it's like a Tuckerology thing or
Speaker 21: the Tucker two-step
thing.
Speaker 21: where tucker doesn't like the war with iran for understandable reasons but he's insistent he's adamant
Speaker 33: that the war was fundamentally engineered or orchestrated by israel and donald trump yet again in year 11
of him
Speaker 33: being the most dominant national political figure is constantly being led astray by all these devious conniving manipulating influences that
Speaker 33: That always somehow end up convincing him to depart from his true pure hearted instincts, which I guess are supposed to be antithetical to, quote, neocons, whatever we mean by that in 2026 or some such variation of this argument. Because if Tucker had to acknowledge what I maintain is the case, that this war with Iran flows ineluctably from Trump's.
very
Speaker 33: clearly articulated second-term ideology
Speaker 21: around global conquest, around resource extraction, around his own personal megalomania, and is very
Speaker 33: much understandable or interpretable from that standpoint, then Tucker and people of that ilk would have to sort of acknowledge that they
Speaker 21: participated in
Speaker 21: Peddling a totally fantastical and nonsensical image of Trump in 2024 when
Speaker 16: Tucker, for instance, decided to formally endorse him, go around campaigning with him, deliver speeches at the Republican convention and on the campaign trail, and tell the voters or the voters that he had a connection to that Trump represented or was a harbinger of something radically different than he ended up being. and that should have been clear at the time because I was pointing it out contemporaneously. So
I think there's
Speaker 16: up there's sort of like a sort
Speaker 21: of some political chicanery going on right now with the monomaniacal myopic overemphasis on israel as somehow the prime mover of this iran war that's not to say that israel is not an adjunct to trump in waging the war or that netanyahu himself hasn't been committed for decades to the objective of overthrowing the iranian government but there's almost like this weird fatalism that's being promoted now among this tucker sort of cohort Thank you.
And I
Speaker 21: have to say, kind of includes the American
Speaker 33: conservative to
some degree
Speaker 33: where, oh, the Israel lobby is just so all powerful, insurmountable that Trump was just no match for them. He's been subjugated by Israel. I saw Kurt say that recently, subjugated by Israel because it's much less comfortable to acknowledge that Trump barreled into office in twenty twenty five.
And
Speaker 33: outlining a very clear and constantly repeated ideology around this global conquest harebrained scheme he's got going on where, you know, Venezuela to Iran,
Speaker 16: not to Cuba, we had the Greenland thing, he declared himself the ruler of Venezuela, the ruler of Gaza, take it over the Panama Canal, who knows what will cook up next. Yeah.
It's
Speaker 16: much more comfortable to, instead, displace all blame or the vast, vast majority of blame or agency or responsibility onto this nefarious interloper of Israel rather than reckon, honestly, with Donald Trump because
a lot of
Speaker 16: people have been invested in Trump or portraying a certain image of Trump that I just think is not supportable by the facts and evidence
Speaker 62: and hasn't been for a long time but now is almost outrageously non-tenable. Yeah.
All
Speaker 64: right, there was a lot there. You blended the first and second topics of
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): the debate and just kind of hit both there. Kurt, do you want to start tackling that? Like for the first item
Speaker 65 (lower-pitched voice): was Israel's influence in in Trump deciding to wage war in Iran. So I do want to kind
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): of go through the systematically. But do you want to get started there, Kurt? And if you want to address the other stuff, too, about you can go ahead.
Speaker 45: um yeah
i mean i think it's interesting to
Speaker 45: the extent that i
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): understand michael's perspective in following the work which i think is probably pretty closely though maybe not as closely as everybody um i think the word overcorrection is interesting which is i think michael has a talent for spotting hypocrisies and contradictions um that are real
um and
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): potentially
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Right. So if all you were doing or reading Michael's work, you would think that Israel had no impact on foreign policy and you would think that Jeffrey Epstein was just a guy. Right. And I think, you know, Michael, basically, you don't support the war. Correct. Right.
of
Speaker 47: course of course not
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): yeah well but again of course i don't support it that is yeah yeah yeah just i'm not i'm trying to make this friendly i'm not yeah yeah yeah like uh you know i don't think
anything
Speaker 67: personally so
go
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): ahead that'd be hard if you want somebody who didn't know i've known you very loosely for about 10 years like somebody who just came up to your work like this year might actually be
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): confused that you don't support the war in ron right because like the the that's fair that's fair i think i think like the like
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): a super majority of your public commentary is just very
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): critical of the right-wing critics of the war. Now, that's not to say that, like, you're not allowed to do that. It's just, like, the emphasis, I think, is kind of curious. I actually don't really know at this
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): point where you think of Epstein, but I assume you don't think he's a totally benign, random guy who lucked into having the
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): world's greatest Rolodex, right? I mean, you assume he has some kind of connections to intelligence, right?
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): some kind of inappropriate sex scheme, right? I mean, he was convicted of it. His
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): paramour and accomplice was also convicted of it, right? But if you just read most of what you write, you would think that this is just an enormous miscarriage of justice that this guy is getting
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): blamed for all this stuff. And so I realize what I'm saying
at a
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): certain point is a defense of just because it's
It's
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): directionally true that any kind of abuse of the truth or any kind of gliding over the facts can be excused. I'm not saying that, but I do think it's an interesting kind of overcorrection to what you perceive as an overcorrection. Because I think, I assume, I mean, you are a kind of left-wing anti-war journalist, right? And like, these are, you
know,
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): pro-war facets of oligarchy. And so it's just a...
I
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): think it's a strange
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): kind of focus as far as I'm concerned.
I
Speaker 71: mean, I think the focus to me is totally rational because there are faulty, fatally flawed perceptions being promoted from the online ecosystem, online media ecosystem, which I partially inhabit, that are putting out,
Speaker 16: I think, a wholly inaccurate picture of how it is that the United States decided on February 28th, 2026. to go to
Speaker 72: work.
Speaker 72: with Iran. I mean, and I don't know how anybody could be seriously confused about my stance on the
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): war. How would you describe that? And like, try to be fair. Be fair to your opponent.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): How would you describe this sort of median Tucker-verse, you know, like, let's not do Candace Owens. Let's not do Ian Carroll. Let's not do... What is the median
Speaker 74: Tucker acolyte think?
I mean, we
Speaker 16: could just stick with Tucker himself, but yeah, I think Tucker is very influential. So people tend to echo the stuff he puts out. What do you think? Yeah, I think Trump was
Speaker 33: manipulated or induced or cajoled or pressured or some will even say blackmailed. That's alluded
Speaker 75: to. And you deny all of this. You don't think you don't think it had any.
I
Speaker 33: think it's being wildly overstated as a proximate cause of the war in order to displace agency away from Trump, who's the commander in chief.
Speaker 33: But
Speaker 45: so, again, I don't want
to
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): make this a boring conversation. I have said publicly that Trump is to blame. I mean, so, like, I have, and I don't think my commentary has been easy on Trump, but, like, I think it's sort of setting up this false test where, like, if I don't 100% blame Trump, if the Tucker Coalition doesn't 100% blame Trump, what Tucker's doing publicly is his own thing. We can get into that, but I'm not Tucker, so I'd prefer to just discuss the issues. Sure.
um i
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): think that israel set the table and donald trump ate the meal and so i think the conditions of this are 50 on the lobby you would agree that the israel lobby exists right i mean do you think that meersheimer and waltz this is okay okay yeah but i don't i don't
Speaker 76: totally agree with their thesis
but i
Speaker 77: think they gave it they i think they made a valuable i mean i first read their book in like 2007 yeah so
Speaker 45: well you think
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): it's a fair piece of scholarship right yeah yeah okay so like and again Again, someone might be confused, and again, not trying to make it over-personalized,
but
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): That
a
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): lot of your fellow travelers in sort of attacking Tucker, attacking the anti-war right, et cetera, et cetera, actually don't think the Israel lobby is a fair piece of scholarship, right? They think there's nothing to it. I mean, you're very sui generis, and I would just submit that your focus is interesting we're talking about, or I'm talking about it, but I think it's kind of
Speaker 78: myopic.
You know, I don't
Speaker 2: think it's myopic, because I am arguing, or
Speaker 16: the argument that
I'm
Speaker 16: increasingly making and increasingly convinced is true, is that the 2024 election was a pinnacle of American propaganda because
it innovated
Speaker 16: ways to rope in the online media ecosystem, which at that point was burgeoning and perhaps
even...
Speaker 16: superseding the traditional media and influence and we have people like tucker at the forefront of it and have these all these podcast guys who are much more influential than i don't know caitlin collins at cnn or something putting out this blinkered version of
Speaker 71: trump as this deep state avenger squad leader who's going to end all the wars and my issue
is
Speaker 71: That, I think, needs to be reckoned with, not to say it's like a niche or weird sort of fixation on it, but because we want to understand how this war came about in the
Speaker 33: most accurate way possible, right?
And if
Speaker 33: your understanding is that you voted for Trump or you listened to these podcasters and supported Trump in 2024 on anti-war grounds and you're just totally flummoxed by how he could have ratcheted up the bellicosity against Iran
–
My
Speaker 33: point is you must have just either not known about or ignored or decided to buy into this ludicrous spin of his
record from the
Speaker 33: first term and then projected some false understanding of Trump onto him in by 2024. So in the annals of American war propaganda, I do think that that is something that needs to be dissected. Now I'm interested in the war itself. I've commented, I mean,
Speaker 33: I could pull up a million tweets and
Speaker 79: sub stack excerpts and podcasts that I've been on where I'm just straightforwardly
Speaker 21: critical of the war on its own terms without even any reference to these more meta discursive issues.
But I
Speaker 21: think one reason maybe I focus a little bit more on these meta discursive issues is because nobody does.
Speaker 33: I was going crazy in 2024 trying to point out.
How
Speaker 33: an eventuality
Speaker 80: like this was eminently foreseeable, and it was totally penalized by the algorithm in
a way that I
Speaker 80: think spoke to the potency of
Speaker 82: that propaganda that
Speaker 21: was going on in 2024.
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): 2024 was a weird year. I think you're implying something more like a conspiracy.
Speaker 55: No, no conspiracy. Just effective propaganda. Yeah.
Speaker 55: media cynicism or something like this uh
you
Speaker 83: know group think
Speaker 33: confirmation bias audience capture a whole host of different dynamics that i think congealed into creating this false
Speaker 84: 100 chance we're roughly thereabouts of an iran war in 2020 i thought there
Speaker 85: was 100 chance and i said so at the time that if you were voting
Speaker 33: for trump on the assumption that you were voting for a policy of reduced bellicosity against iran that you were in la la land
He
Speaker 33: said
Speaker 86: this at the time?
Speaker 33: Yeah.
Speaker 87: So I
Speaker 88: also pointed out how he would, you know, he also gave just outright speeches and statements where he was threatening to blow the whole of Iran to smithereens,
Speaker 33: where he was preemptively endorsing the idea of a joint U.S.-Israeli strike campaign against Iranian
Speaker 16: nuclear facilities. And, you know.
I
Speaker 16: guess I could have just started to ask his Steve Whitcoff for the first six months of the second Trump administration
Speaker 33: and pretended that something was going on that plainly wasn't. But, yeah, I do find it to be maddening in a way that I think warrants some extra journalistic focus in addition to the coverage and the commentary and the research that I have also done on the war itself. Because I'm a student of American politics.
Speaker 33: Propaganda. I compare Trump to Richard Nixon in 1968, where he's Richard Dixon in
Speaker 21: 1968 said, and Peter Hitchens shared this at the time. So I was even trying to make the argument that in a way that was amenable to conservatives. Richard
Dixon in
Speaker 21: 1968. I know you're a Nixon guy, right? Because both from Orange County. Is that right? Yeah.
Speaker 21: I like him too. I think he's a fascinating figure. I've listened to like hours upon hours of those interviews he did with Frank Gannon, his former aide in the early 80s. And he's very learned, very, very definitely intelligent, definitely very well-informed. He's a person with a brain. Yeah, yeah, exactly. So I'm into him as a historical figure. But Richard Nixon in 1968 said that he has a secret plan to solve the Vietnam War.
Or
Speaker 21: peace with honor. And Trump, likewise, always had a secret plan to solve
the
Speaker 88: Ukraine war in 24 hours. He
had a
Speaker 88: secret plan to bring peace to the Middle East, etc, etc, etc. And he never
Speaker 33: got pressed on
it for
Speaker 33: specifics when he did all these dopey podcasts that were part of this consensus that unified behind him.
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, Kurt, before you respond, I know we're adding a lot of things here, but we're going to go through some specifics that I think need to be drilled down
Speaker 64: on. But just so people watching this or listening to this know, we're going to go through some of this methodically. But Kurt, I'll let you respond first. By the way, remind me to address the Epstein point
Speaker 92: as well, because that was sort of a strange characterization. Go ahead.
Speaker 64: Kurt, I feel like you
Speaker 93: want to respond and then we can circle back to some of the Israel stuff in a second. We'll
Speaker 94: get to it.
Speaker 95: Well, I mean, I
Speaker 93: think
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): that history was far more fluid and contingent than Michael's implying. So, I mean, the administration opened up negotiations with the Iranians.
The
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Biden administration didn't do that. Trump didn't negotiate directly with the Iranians in term one. I think these were all real things that happened. I think there were.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): There was and is an impression within the administration that the anti-war right, the podcast right is a real thing, is a real constituency that they don't want to lose. They leaned on it for their campaign. I think it is potentially moderating elements of the conduct of the war right now. And I think Trump is a coalition manager. I think he's chosen poorly. And I think this war is a disgrace.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): But fundamentally, this is not somebody who is up there like George W. Bush, who has like a firm conviction in any of this. And I think he is at some level self-evidently venal. And he's in the pocket of the Israel lobby and potentially more. He could be intimidated. And I don't think the Epstein thing
is the
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): secret to the universe, but I think there's something there.
And
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): I think it's I think it's strange that the timeline lines up exactly with the
Speaker 97 (lower-pitched voice): ramp up of the war last summer. And what's the causation there? Cause it.
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): Well, I mean, like what's how does that correlate?
I don't know, because like
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): we don't have all the information because the government is not releasing it. And so which is why it's strange. I mean.
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): Again, I'm
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): not arguing that you are arguing that the government shouldn't release all the information. I
assume you
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): think the government should release all the information, right? I
Speaker 79: criticized Thomas Massey when he introduced his legislation with Ro Khanna because they decided to include these giant carve-outs that I said months before
Speaker 98: the Epstein files transparency act was passed would result in these superfluous redactions. So, yes, I'm in favor of maximum transparency. But
Speaker 99: anyway, only Massey and Conner are doing anything. So, I mean, it's
Speaker 100: this sort of like randomly slandering.
A
Speaker 100: bunch of like an auto mechanic and an I.T. manager in
Speaker 71: New York City as complicit in child sex crimes and then not even having the decency to apologize to them. Well,
how
Speaker 101: is something that they've been doing?
OK,
Speaker 71: OK.
Speaker 102: I
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): think, though, like I think your criticism is perfectionist
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): fundamentally and overly tailored. Explain.
Would you
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): prefer that, that Kana and Massey didn't do any kind of activism on the Epstein story? Because I mean, most of Congress is pliant. And that's a good question. Like, you
take a
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): lot of swings at people that are ostensibly more or less aligned with you. And you currently when I don't think it will be permanent, because I think you're pretty,
uh,
you
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): evolve in your alliances. But you currently are a lot of a lot of people who I think you actually don't even agree with that much.
I don't
Speaker 2: consider myself
really in alliance with
Speaker 2: anyone. I'm not
sure
Speaker 16: who you're referring to. You mean like the quote, neocons or Ben Shapiro or something? I don't consider myself to be in any sort
of alliance
Speaker 16: with those people just because incidentally, we might
have a
Speaker 16: similar perspective on something that, yeah, in the case of Ben Shapiro or Batya
Speaker 33: or these other people is informed by their pro-Israel
Speaker 16: underlying convictions, but that's not what it's informed by for me. I just got done telling you that Max Abrams decided to denounce me as somebody who was like an anti-Semitic something.
Speaker 103 (lower-pitched voice): I'm not arguing like, you know, Sith Lord, you know, you got to pick a side whole thing. I think that would be very on you.
But
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): again, like if someone was just reading your stuff the last six months, they would think
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Michael Tracy, he is the guy who thinks Israel has nothing to do with the Iran war. And he thinks that Jeffrey Epstein
is,
was
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): basically, you know, was railroaded by the United States justice system.
I
Speaker 98: mean, they couldn't have been reading that closely then, because I'll give you an article that I published last. Well, then what am I supposed to do about that? If people don't actually read,
they just
Speaker 98: assume that I'm saying things that I'm not.
Speaker 104: Focus is, is, is, is I'll say it here.
Speaker 2: Look here, here, here's what I wrote in my article on March 18th. I think
it was
Speaker 2: March 12th.
I
Speaker 16: am obviously not denying that Israel is a significant factor in precipitating this war or in U.S. foreign policy in general. It is obviously true that Trump is waging the war in concert with Netanyahu. It is obviously true that toppling the government of Iran has been a decades-long goal of Netanyahu
Speaker 71: and other Israeli political and military officials. Nobody's denying that, or at least I'm not, but promoting Israel as the mythical be-all, end-all explanation only serves to speciously immunize Trump, and therefore his erstwhile propaganda function is sadly like Tucker's.
I
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): think you're fighting a straw man. It's not the end-all, be-all. The primary
Speaker 106: mover, the main agent of responsibility? It's the
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): first mover. Okay,
Speaker 106: so explain how Israel should be understood
as
Speaker 107: the primary agent of responsibility here. You're twisting my words. Tell me what your contention is. The
Speaker 108: responsibility is shared. Israel
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): wanted this. The president of the United States is ceded to it. So it's joint culpability as far as I'm concerned. But
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Trump didn't want
Speaker 109: it.
Trump
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): did it despite his best instincts He would be doing this without Israel which is an almost impossible counterfactual I think is worth pursuing
I
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): don't think Trump has a particular axe to grind with the Iranians Really?
Speaker 19: Doesn't he go around claiming that they were trying to assassinate him? You don't think
he has
Speaker 19: an axe to grind? He
Speaker 98: said that was one of his motivations for launching the war that they
got to
Speaker 98: the Supreme Leader before they got to him
Speaker 110: The historical record there is actually a little murky
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): There's differing accounts
Yes.
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): on the campaign, for instance. Say what you
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): will, I think he's actually a reasonable journalist. Michael Wolff in his book has a number of accounts where he says that Trump would try to encourage people
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Senate candidates who would particularly want Tim Sheehy, who would frequently campaign being like, remember, we liquidated Soleimani, et cetera, et cetera. He would encourage Soleimani not to do that, sorry, Tim Sheehy not to do that, as so not to provoke Iranian assassination squads, these kinds of things. I think it's unclear, and I think this is something that Tucker has actually been
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): very useful for
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): the public record on it's unclear to the degree to which Trump historically has believed in these Iranian assassinations he said he says he believes
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): he says he does now like I mean what what is what is what has happened is that Trump has increasingly adopted neocon rhetoric which is provided for
him
Now,
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): does that mean he has no responsibility? No. But does it also mean that the people that are writing the talking points that are backing him up on this, that are his new kitchen cabinet, are irrelevant? Also, no. I mean, he is not an ideological neocon. He is not George W. Bush. He never ran as one. Maybe he ran
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): as nothing. Maybe he ran as all things to all men. That's potentially a more interesting thesis. Well, he did run as somebody.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Let Kurt finish.
Speaker 113: The idea
Speaker 111: that he has run as an unreconstructed, actually the people in
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): 2016 who led the Never Trump movement against me, that's true MAGA. Actually, I am the sole arbiter of what MAGA is. So like that's something he never said on the campaign trail, right? Like, hey, you Muslim cleric who's voting for
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): me in Michigan, actually, I control MAGA.
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): what uh what maga
Speaker 8: is if you vote for me it's not what he did
now
Speaker 114: you can say he's a jackass he's a cynic he's a psychopath uh but he politics
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): insofar as that approach went and i do think it's
relevant and i
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): do think that if you had run the simulation a number of times i'm not sure it would go like this i think the fundamental thing that happened is the lobby is very powerful uh the republican establishment loves this
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Seemingly, the members of Congress would rather the
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Iran War keep going than keep their seats. You know, I mean, this is this is bad for them in the midterms. You would think they would be lobbying for the war to stop. There is some reporting that they're doing that in private, but in public, basically no one is opposed to it on the Hill on the Republican
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): side.
And,
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): you know, I think the idea that he always was this iteration
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): of himself was.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): talking like Mark
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): Levin, telling people to watch Mark Thiessen, I think is a bit of a retcon of history. I don't
Speaker 115: know. I remember Mark Levin being invited to Hanukkah celebrations at the White House
in the
Speaker 115: first time. He
Speaker 45: was always in a coalition. So for my own perspective, I always knew this was
a
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): risk. And you can say I got the trade wrong and the Iran war is kind of like my
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): Rubicon, third rail, can't
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): crush, I mean, so that's, I'm the guy who went on Tucker the night of Soleimani's assassination and denounced it. Very presumably the president of the United States watched that. You know, I am
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): incandescent and unbelievably disappointed by this.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): But the idea that it was a known known that this was going to happen like this, you must be operating with more information than me.
Speaker 16: Maybe so. I mean, I just think that there should be more introspection and self-criticism as to how something like this could have come as such a shock, apparently, or even come as something that was like a
Speaker 21: downside risk or sort of almost like a negligible outcome that didn't need to be emphasized in real time.
Speaker 21: Because I don't know,
Speaker 16: do you recall Trump in 2024 being bashful about bragging that he's the most pro-Israel president of all time and
Speaker 21: that he was going to ratchet it up even further in a second term? Even as he was going
Speaker 116: around to Dearborn,
Speaker 103 (lower-pitched voice): Michigan and throwing a bone to some imams who didn't really have a great grasp of the issue? He also used Joe Biden to being genocide Joe.
He was
Speaker 103 (lower-pitched voice): just repeating
a
Speaker 118: funny thing that somebody chanted.
In
Speaker 9: terms
Speaker 79: of anything that could be discerned about his policy record, okay, let's go to this. So when Trump wins the 2024
Speaker 33: election, right,
he's got maximum
Speaker 33: political capital through, if we look at the entire
Speaker 21: scope of his time as a national political figure.
When
Speaker 21: he wins the 2024 elections, when he has the most political capital, I think that's fair to say, because he wins the popular vote, he wins all the swing states, as he likes to remind us, there's no issue of a electoral college, you know, snafu as in 2016. And so he starts to choose
personnel for
Speaker 16: his second administration. Who does he choose as his secretary of state, who's now got this hybrid Henry Kissinger role and is probably more influential?
Speaker 16: than anybody
Speaker 21: to occupy a similar position since Kissinger. He picks Marco Rubio, who's long known to have been one of
Speaker 16: the most ardent anti-Iran hawks and just hawks in general in the United States Senate, as the person that he perceives as best suited to carry out his foreign policy goals. He picks Mike Waltz
Speaker 21: as his national security advisor initially,
which is
Speaker 21: not even subject to Senate confirmation, so he could have picked Fred Flintstone if he wanted to.
as
Speaker 21: somebody who he wants in the White House constantly helping him
Speaker 71: to organize his foreign policy
Speaker 120: portfolio. What does that
Speaker 9: reflect about Trump? Did Israel swindle him into making those picks? How
far back
Speaker 79: does this go? A lot of people love to talk about this quote from Rubio the week after the war
where
The idea
Speaker 33: was that something like Israel was going to strike first of the therefore the United States got dragged in and had to go to war because Israel was going to be instigating it. Well, I don't know. Excuse me.
Did
Speaker 121: Netanyahu somehow bamboozle Trump into amassing the largest U.S. military presence in the Middle East since 2003? Ahead of
Speaker 88: that, like.
Speaker 88: timing, you know, window of timing. And I don't know, did anybody see the reporting in Politico
Speaker 122: and elsewhere where they were like, they were coordinating amongst themselves in the US and Israelis about like, who should go first? What would be the most politically palatable? Was Israel ghostwriting Truth Social in January, where Trump was calling
Speaker 121: for Iranians to take over every government institution and saying, I'll be right there to help you? Like, how far does this influence go? Where, yeah, of course, the
Speaker 9: pro-Israel lobby is in the ambience in Washington, DC. Nobody's denying
it.
Speaker 9: that but again in order to get trump off the hook still to this day on some level people talk about it as though it's just this behemoth and insurmountable as though obama didn't pursue the iran nuclear deal over the bitter objections
Speaker 122: of the quote israel lobby and defeated them in his second
Speaker 123: term you you are positing two things
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): at
once
Speaker 123: and then
weirdly
Speaker 124: downgrading
One of
Speaker 124: them. You can see that an Israel lobby exists
and you
Speaker 124: can see that it's highly influential.
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): Okay, okay. Just for the rest, because it's not a point of emphasis as far as I can tell
in your
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): recent journalism.
Speaker 126: Secondarily, you are arguing... I've emphasized it a lot, actually, over the years. Not recently. In
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): my view. Secondarily, you are saying that Trump
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): has this clear ideology
that is
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): overwhelmingly hawkish, imperial,
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): zyophilic Iran hawkish this is actually
who he
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): is this is what he believes he cares about it he's willing
to use
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): political capital on it and it is just entirely happening
independent of
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): this very powerful
lobby that you
Speaker 128: can see exists in conjunction
Speaker 129: with in synergy with I would say
well certainly in synergy
Speaker 129: with
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): yeah but like you think that Donald Trump who
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): It was kind of about him.
It was kind of
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): about being popular.
It was kind
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): of about self-enrichment.
It was
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): kind of about
Speaker 130: being well- Not liking Iran. I mean, he's made that pretty clear since
he came
Speaker 130: down the escalator.
Yeah, yeah. You were
Speaker 45: arguing that he is taking it in the teeth, taking it on the chin, letting gas prices go above $4 a gallon, letting oil go above $120 a gallon,
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): letting his earliest supporters in media denounce him or not denounce him enough for your skin. And
he's doing this
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): out of conviction. I think it,
Speaker 131: yeah, it largely is conviction driven. Just like I thought that Joe Biden's policy in Ukraine was largely
Speaker 79: conviction driven because he was the guy that Bill Clinton delegated to run the NATO expansion in the 1990s. And there was a lot that could be traced back to
Speaker 132: Biden. I know,
Speaker 80: but like Donald Trump's he'd been in the, So in 2016,
Speaker 80: I would have been more hesitant to
Speaker 133: ascribe Trump with any kind of clear-cut ideological motivations. But then once we got four years of data from the first term, and then four years of him being the kingmaker in the Republican Party during the interregnum period...
Speaker 133: And then the rhetoric on the campaign trail, the personnel, the influences, there does become an ideology that emerges that is much more decipherable. So I guess I would just ask you, I mean, do you think that Trump's actual convictions inform this at all? Like, why is it that he came into office in the second term? If
you go back
Speaker 133: and read his inaugural address, he's invoking William McKinley as the model that he wants to emulate in terms of foreign policy. William McKinley was the first U.S. president to ever send.
Speaker 133: u.s soldiers on expeditionary overseas missions to conquer foreign lands like the philippines and guam that's who trump or his speech writers who are trying to channel his instincts that's who trump was citing as his model for the second term then we start hearing about wanting to seize greenland wanting to seize canada
i guess
Speaker 133: that was a joke but it stopped being funny after a
He
Speaker 133: declares himself the ruler of Gaza. So he told the imams in Michigan, right, that he wants to get the war over with or something, which means allowing expediting munitions to Israel so they can pulverize Gaza harder and faster and victory can be declared and a ceasefire can be brokered that
will then
Speaker 133: allow the U.S. and Israel to rearm for an Iran confrontation.
Speaker 133: Trump didn't let the emails in on that secret. Then we have Venezuela where he's taking the oil. So like, I mean, I think you would acknowledge, right? That to the extent we can identify any ideological
Speaker 80: through line in Donald Trump, going back to his first appearance on the public stage, let's trace it to 2015, and now has been much more fleshed out and made real and reified in the second term, which is organized around just
Speaker 80: actualizing Trump's sort of unfettered ambitions and desires in contrast with the first term where he faced some bureaucratic roadblocks, right? And some personnel choices who were a little bit inimical to him. This is true Trump. This is what we got in the second term. This is what people were voting for.
And he's
Speaker 80: been saying for a long time, take the oil. His big critique of George W. Bush was, yeah, maybe some of the death and destruction in Iraq wasn't great, but if you're going to go in, take the oil.
And
Speaker 80: then sure enough, Trump does set up a policy in Syria in the first term where he takes the oil so that the revenues can't go into the central Assad government
at the time. Now
Speaker 80: he's taken the oil in Venezuela, just like he tried to do regime change in Venezuela in the first term. But it was a much more haphazard attempt. And he's taken the natural resources in Ukraine through the so-called minerals deal and sent Besson to organize.
So is
Speaker 80: this not an ideology at some point that could help explain why it is that now he's also saying he wants to take the oil in
Venezuela?
Speaker 80: Iran once he's done with it and personally controlled the state of Hormuz. Whereas it's just all
Speaker 135: so random and nothing can be extrapolated from it. He
Speaker 45: obviously has views, but you're arguing that there is a Trumpism, which is a
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): controversial argument, and then you're arguing that Trumpism is basically a more amoral version
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): of what Ben Shapiro thinks. I just think this is just a way over determined argument. I mean, my...
It
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): just
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): doesn't allow for any of the sort of roller coasters of policy that we've seen with Trump. We saw Trump negotiate with the Iranians. We saw Trump bomb the Iranians. We saw Trump give the Ukrainians what some alleged are a pro-Russian or even Russian talking points
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): deal. Then
we see
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): Trump at the U.N. saying that we need to take back all of Ukraine. The guy vacillates all the time. And fundamentally... What's the policy?
There's policy
Speaker 137: continuity.
Speaker 137: That kind of
Speaker 45: cuts through the noise in terms of his scattershot. Okay, Kurt, explain. Negotiation. He has no patience for negotiation.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): And so war is the super button that he can press.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): And pretty much from Soleimani to Baghdadi to Borat
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): bagging Maduro to even the 12-day war, although we saw cracks of his stress there at the end, you know,
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): neither of these guys know what they're doing, quote, pretty much has been a super button that has worked for him. Now,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): I'll always add that, you know, none of these things heightened his popularity. None of them helped him. It didn't hurt him either by the polls, not much. And so he pressed the button
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): again.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): under pressure, too? I mean, is it not relevant that Netanyahu flew to Mar-a-Lago over
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): Christmas?
And is
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): it not relevant that all of a sudden the wrong crisis started right then and there? Is it not relevant? What? Of course it's relevant. But
Speaker 79: could it also be the case that Trump has used Netanyahu as an ideological fellow traveler in lots of ways, and they can therefore collaborate to achieve Trump's
Speaker 82: desired objectives?
Speaker 139: They're not ideological fellow travelers.
Apparently
Speaker 82: they are.
So
Speaker 139: they're not ideologically aligned on this
Speaker 140: war with Iran?
Netanyahu is a
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): right-wing Zionist Jewish-American or kind of
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): American guy, right? I think it's fair to say. He is a small government figure within Israel.
He
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): is a political, no, that's actually, that's his domestic policies,
Speaker 141: like deregulation, Reaganomics. Right, yeah, yeah. Yeah. Liberalization, economic. Liberal, whatever, yeah.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): And like, you know, he's kind of a normie con in like the American tradition. That's why he was feted around the Bush
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): administration. That's why he was close both personally and ideologically with Mitt Romney. But not Barack Obama.
Not
Speaker 143 (lower-pitched voice): Barack Obama.
Yeah,
Speaker 143 (lower-pitched voice): yeah, yeah. So, I mean, Netanyahu is a fairly established entity. Trump is all over the place, has a completely different background.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): The idea that they really, like, super agree on that much as human beings or as political animals, I think it's just overstated.
Well, they seem to
Speaker 71: agree enough on Iran that Trump decided for the first time in history to launch joint military
Speaker 144: offenses. I think he's under a tremendous amount of pressure to do it, and he's buckled. By
Speaker 145: who? By Bibi?
Speaker 145: Yeah, by Bibi, by Mossad, by the whole thing. By Mossad? Sure. So what's the pressure that
Speaker 146: Mossad is exerting? Is this where the Epstein angle comes in as well, like their sexual
Speaker 147: blackmail? I think the Epstein stuff is relevant. Okay, so explain that theory.
We don't have
Speaker 145: all the information. No, but if you're saying it's relevant, on what basis is it relevant? You're the one who's willing to say –
What
Speaker 148: information do you have that leads you to believe that it's relevant? So Kurt, you're speculating that
Speaker 149: Epstein
Speaker 150: might be associated with this?
Yeah.
Put
Speaker 150: me out on a limb. Yes, yes. But based on what?
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): Based
on how
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): strange he is behaving around this investigation and based on Jeffrey Epstein's clear ties to Israel.
Speaker 21: Okay.
And you're
Speaker 21: saying that could be a causal factor in why the United States is at war with Iran? I think it is relevant.
But, you
Speaker 133: know, I'm constantly being pressed to provide evidence for my statements around Jeffrey Epstein, which I'm
Speaker 21: happy to do because, unfortunately, I know way too much of the primary source material. But then you could just toss out some kind of like vaguely speculative claim, and that's sufficient without any real evidence.
Speaker 151: I think you mentioned
a financial incentive. Are
Speaker 98: you claiming like there's a sexual blackmail situation that's coercing Trump into? It's possible.
Okay, but
Speaker 98: no evidence for that.
No evidence, in
Speaker 21: fact, at all that Jeffrey Epstein blackmailed anyone, which is
what the
Speaker 21: FBI concluded in internal memoranda in the so-called Epstein files that they never
thought were going to see
Speaker 21: the light of day. I
think there are
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): ways of blackmailing people that are less overt than you're implying.
Like
Speaker 152: what? I
mean, why
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): are there
Speaker 141: cameras in all the guys' pictures? Why
is he
Speaker 141: taking pictures? There are
Speaker 152: cameras. See, this is, okay. So, I mean, if you're going to posit that Jeffrey Epstein is somehow a potentially
Speaker 100: decisive reason why Trump.
Speaker 100: attacked Iran maybe you should learn some of the basic details of the Epstein case which is that there were not cameras in every bedroom and bathroom
Speaker 154: which
Speaker 113: rooms which rooms were they in I say something and then you take the maximal interpretation of what
it is tell me
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): what you're saying about the cameras I
believe that there
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): are first hand accounts of cameras inside of pictures in his properties
Speaker 155: first hand accounts by whom people who went to his house inside of pictures Thank you.
Speaker 156: Yes.
So
Speaker 155: you're not talking about hidden cameras in bedrooms or –
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, like inside of – like you go into the house and you'd have – Yeah,
Speaker 27: that's in the New York townhouse where Eric Weinstein wove out a whole theory about how he saw a camera in
Speaker 157: a photo in the vestibule. Look, I
know
Speaker 158: Eric recently.
Speaker 157: And then also
Speaker 27: –
Speaker 27: The claims about blackmail came from some of the most unreliable people that ever walked the face of Earth, meaning Maria Farmer, who's just a hallucinatory mess, Virginia Roberts
Speaker 160: Gouffre. I'm sure you don't care about that stuff because it's fun to just kind of excitedly speculate, but like once you drill down the details. I do care. That makes this whole thesis all the more absurd.
And what's it got to do
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): with Trump? Just because the biggest sort of tabloid crazed story of all time
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): has false accusers, has information that doesn't line up,
Speaker 162: doesn't mean that there's not a major story here. What's the story?
The story
Speaker 163: here is, where did this guy get all his money?
We know how he
Speaker 163: got lots of his money. What?
I mean,
Speaker 133: that's an answerable question. It seems like people who constantly pose that question
Speaker 164: don't want to know what information is in the public record that could answer it, at least in large part. We don't have fully comprehensive information, probably.
We know
Speaker 164: this
Speaker 123: guy is emailing people all day and doing all these meetings
Speaker 111: all day. What is he never doing? He's almost never trading anything. He's not managing assets. It's very
Speaker 163: unusual. It's very unusual.
I
Speaker 163: mean,
Speaker 165: he is doing quite a bit of work and the times
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): that at the times that a very good piece on like the most plausible sort of innocent, like rise of Epstein kind of like ladies man who would get, you
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): know, kind of lie BS and get from accounts to accounts. And I'm not arguing that none of that
Speaker 107: happened, but I
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): also think
Speaker 107: at a certain point, like you just don't become
a
Speaker 111: guy who's obviously associated with the CIA, if not Mossad in your mid thirties, obviously associated
Speaker 166: with the CIA, meaning
what?
that he
Speaker 111: met
Speaker 166: with bill burns drops drop site news tax has done a
Speaker 167: number of
Speaker 168: drops drop site news is another
i mean they
Speaker 168: they presuppose they presuppose they
Speaker 79: presuppose the existence if you look at what ryan grimm and murtasa hussein have said they what they
Speaker 121: do is they fish out anything that could be potentially tantalizing that connects
in any way
Speaker 121: to israel
And they
Speaker 121: folk and they they amplify that in
Speaker 79: connection to Epstein and they take for granted that Epstein, yes, was also on top of that running a globe spanning child
sex
Speaker 133: trafficking and blackmail operation. So then when some little snippet of info comes out on Israel, we all then take that in the context of this larger operation he's supposedly running for which there's no evidence of
Speaker 169: the narrative. You're angry
about
Speaker 123: it. I understand. I'm not angry about it. You think nothing's going on? You think I never
Speaker 170: said nothing is going on. there's lots going on. I've probably read more of
Speaker 170: material than anybody's
Speaker 171: thinking that you are asserting that you think nothing is going on
like i'm asking
Speaker 121: what you're asserting and then i'm questioning whether there's satisfactory evidence for it i never said there's nothing going on with jeffrey epstein obviously he did have one of
Speaker 173 (lower-pitched voice): the most amazing rolodexes in world history an individual likely connected to one if not more intelligence agencies likely
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): israel's
he is a
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): player within politics finance and celebrity in the United States and abroad.
He's
Speaker 174: connected to Israel. He's connected to France. He's connected
Speaker 98: to Britain. He's connected to the United States. He's connected to Saudi Arabia. He's connected to lots of top government
Speaker 79: officials in lots of countries, but people hone in on Israel exclusively. So they don't even know that he has, for example, connections to French government officials, that they hone in on Israel exclusively.
Speaker 79: Because then that
Speaker 121: allows them to create this elaborate sort of interpretive paradigm for things that go on in the world that is somehow Israel pulling the strings, which
Speaker 9: I object to because I've always been trying to impart on people the need for a rational critique of Israel, not a critique
Speaker 121: of Israel where you just...
You
Speaker 121: insinuate things like Tucker does. I'm not saying you agree with Tucker 100%, but you insinuate things that Israel's behind the assassination of Charlie Kirk. They're behind a massive child rape and blackmail operation. They're behind...
Speaker 121: beguiling Trump into bombing Iran.
Speaker 9: Everything that goes wrong now, it seems, is ultimately sourceable to Israel in a way that I don't think gives us a good apprehension of what the Israel lobby is or the influence that it
Speaker 79: exerts. I covered these democratic primaries, the AIPAC,
Speaker 79: actually intervened in in a somewhat unusual way for them by actually you know endorsing candidates and spending against you know jamal bowman and cory bush and so forth and trying to get in these more conventionally pro-israel democrats i'm all in favor of covering
Speaker 9: that stuff i object though when israel becomes this totalizing narrative that then just gives you this like sort of easy way to rationalize stuff and not acknowledge that trump has had this resource extraction ideology i mean does trump have any ideology at all like if you have you
Speaker 9: Did you listen to his inaugural address? Do you hear him talk
Speaker 88: about how he now wants to be taking Cuba because he's so thrilled with how his other conquests have been going? What do we make of that? What does Israel have to do with England or Cuba or
Speaker 177: Venezuela? He has a
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): mercantilist, zero-sum economic view of the world.
I
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): think you see that in his inability to manage the Iran crisis. He thinks that just because the U.S. has a bunch of oil and gas that
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): U.S. consumers will be shielded from a global market.
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): Right.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): I mean, like this is pretty obvious. So I'm not the one making these sort of totalizing arguments. I'm arguing he has certain views. These views become salient at certain times and less salient at other times. And I'm arguing that Israel is a major player. And I'm arguing that Jeffrey Epstein is highly
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): associated with Israel.
Speaker 16: Right. So you're sort of dot
Speaker 33: connecting. Israel is influential in American politics. Jeffrey Epstein may have had some, quote, connections or ties to Israel. So we're doing almost like Russiagate redux, right? Because you
Speaker 84: could always posit some tie between Russia and the Trump orbit, right? There's far more substantiation for Israelgate than Russiagate.
i'm not
Speaker 178: sure i mean there were some quote ties
Speaker 179: if you want to use that loose terminology saying i stand with russia and you
Speaker 79: might recall i was one of the very few first people with any media adjacency whatsoever to get involved from a critical perspective on the russia gate thing back in july of 2016 when jeffrey goldberg was first whipping it up in the atlantic along with david from and so forth and yeah i do think that now this russia gate thing is this uh epstein thing rather is taking on almost this
Speaker 79: weird parallel universe character of this it's Russiagate but for the people who wanted to support Trump on anti-interventionist grounds now
they have
Speaker 79: their own little Russiagate where like every dot can be spuriously connected
and it
Speaker 79: goes back to Israel and that's what's
Speaker 80: pulling the strings with Trump and Jeffrey Epstein like we don't know
Speaker 180: for sure that
he had
Speaker 180: the cameras in the bedroom but Eric Weinstein said something on a podcast in 2019 you
Speaker 181: don't
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): concede
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): nuance and the nuance i should concede to i've just laid out a lot more nuance than how you are
so i
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): agree that
Speaker 182: israel's
influential
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): then what
are we like
Speaker 183: arguing about the proportionality
Speaker 79: of the influence that's being currently assigned to israel vis-a-vis the commander-in-chief donald trump who did this historic feat of winning a non-consecutive
Speaker 80: term in 2024 to fulfill his ideological ambitions, that stuff is
Speaker 80: all being shunted to the side so we can all monomaniacally focus on the
Speaker 79: podcast circuit on Israel and Tucker and whatnot. That's my problem. It's not being shunted to the
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): side of it. If anything, you see timidness from the Democratic leadership to oppose this war or to investigate Israel. If
Speaker 45: anything, it's being ghettoized. Just a bunch of people you know.
Speaker 185: How about the American Conservative? What do you mean? I mean, do you think that the proportionality is correct
Speaker 185: as to Trump's own I
Speaker 79: know I spoke to Scott McConnell who was the founder of the American Conservative who is now despondent because he says that he bought into this whole line, hook, line and sinker in 2024 even though he had been very wary in the
Speaker 133: first Trump term about Trump's policy actions on Iran in particular you might remember I covered Tulsi Gabbard before anybody did and I knew her personally very well and
Speaker 133: could recite her positions probably with enough specificity to a fault. And I was with her in New Hampshire the day that Trump decided
to drone
Speaker 133: strike assassinate Qasem Soleimani, the most revered military figure in Iran, when he was on some diplomatic mission to Iraq. And you know what Tulsi Gabbard said at the time? Because I still got it on my phone. War
crime, Trump
Speaker 186: should be impeached.
Speaker 133: She said that Trump has instigated on false premises a state of war with Iran that is going to invariably lead to a regime change
Speaker 133: war by concocting a false imminent threat. Now, Tulsi Capper was amazingly
Speaker 187: prescient when she pointed that out with Trump. But then it all got sort of obscured. She
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): probably thought, she probably meant in 2020, not in 2026.
Well,
Speaker 188: yeah, I mean,
if Trump
Speaker 188: retained power, that's why she was saying, at least
at the time,
Speaker 188: who
Speaker 98: knows what she thinks now, that she was running to defeat him. Do you agree with Joe Kent's resignation letter
where he
Speaker 98: says that, you know, the main explanation for
this war
is
Speaker 121: that Trump was
Speaker 9: deceived by Israel just as George W. Bush was similarly deceived by Israel to invade Iraq. Really? Is that the all-consuming thesis we're going with now?
Not
Speaker 173 (lower-pitched voice): the word that I would have chosen, but I think Kent's letter was heroic and accurate, basically. I
think it spoke to
Speaker 189: some personal integrity to actually resign, unlike Tulsi. But then he puts
Speaker 190: out all this nonsense that kind of just muddles the issue. Why
did you
Speaker 190: bring up the magazine?
Well, because
Speaker 21: I wrote for the American Conservative for a number of years. I was pretty aware of the sentiments expressed there. Daniel Larson is somebody who I follow for a long time. He's always been extremely clear-sighted on the
Speaker 16: issue of Trump and Iran in particular. He covered that daily for the American Conservative. He's now independent.
Speaker 33: And there was just nobody sounding these notes at all at the American Conservative in the 2024 election, as I recall.
Speaker 79: Or until very recently, like until February 28th, I guess that was the point of no return. But prior to that, we were getting all this apology for Steve Whitcoff, who I mean, if you're talking about the nefarious influence of Israel on U.S. politics, how did Steve Whitcoff get a pass? This guy was attending IDF fundraisers and Jared gets
Speaker 121: insinuated back into the scene. So, like, I don't know, it just
Speaker 129: seems like we were pretty harsh in the 12 day war.
Speaker 129: We were supportive of the administration pursuing...
Speaker 9: I remember you doing a Steve Whitcoff win counter because he just keeps on winning. I
Speaker 158: thought Whitcoff was... Why?
Speaker 9: Because he did these pretextual bogus negotiations that were... So
Speaker 148: unlike you, Michael... That were structured in such a way that they could never actually lead to a diplomatic outcome? I don't sit here
Speaker 45: and assume doom. I don't assume that I know everything. And so, yeah, Whitcoff's
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): background when he was named in December of 2024 to me was concerning.
I
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): did
Speaker 143 (lower-pitched voice): not
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): think that this implied a guy who was going to do my kind of foreign policy. I thought the transition was disappointing, and I thought that that was case in point. But then three days
Speaker 45: before Trump was ever inaugurated, Wyckoff imposed a ceasefire on the Israelis. That Netanyahu. Okay,
partially with the Biden
Speaker 129: administration, but who had the heft? You know, who's going to be president in three days? I think Mr. Trump. And so...
You
Speaker 129: know, I was like, wow, this guy might be pretty surprising. And then his statements
Speaker 45: about, you know, all we need to
do is
Speaker 45: get a no nuclear weapon deal. That wasn't a no nuclear enrichment. He wasn't talking like that. It's like, hmm, I could do one of two things. It could be like, this guy's a scientist creature that I need to distrust unless he does everything I want and just assume all the worst about him.
Or I
Speaker 45: could say, let's give this guy a chance.
Speaker 45: And he and his team said he flew to
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Amman, which is not so easy to get to, I believe, seven to nine times before the 12-day war. He seemed to be trying. He seemed better than Jared. Jared's college roommate, Adam Buller, the hostage negotiation, said, I think, responsible things about Hamas, which is like, yes, this has a militant wing.
Speaker 45: Obviously, obviously, it is a radical group in many ways. But, you know, their moderate wing are human beings that you could potentially do a durable deal with. That's Adam.
Speaker 45: bowler as a trump administration official close to kushner so these guys weren't made up they didn't stay
Speaker 129: this stuff and like you can believe one of two things you can believe that just you know ultimately it didn't matter or i think the implications of what you're saying
Speaker 113: are actually uh more extreme which is like that they were lying that there was there was a massive cabal no no
Speaker 192: i mean
Speaker 11: i'm not saying i'm not saying there's overt lying necessarily i'm just saying that
We
Speaker 11: should follow the evidence as best we can. And the
Speaker 21: evidence, the evidence
did not
Speaker 21: substantiate, for example, Tucker, I know not you, but Tucker, you know, the leader of this milieu in a way, interviewing Whitcoff early on in the second Trump administration. I think this was March of 2025.
Speaker 133: And here's the headline of that interview. Quote, Steve Whitcoff's critical role in negotiating global peace and the warmongers trying to stop him. So always and ever.
Speaker 133: it's this mythical showdown between Trump and his close confidants like Whitcoff from the New York and South Florida real estate world. They're always clashing with the so-called neocons or establishment. It's never the case that Lindsey Graham and Donald Trump might have convergent interests and beliefs. I mean, it must just be a total coincidence that
Speaker 80: Lindsey Graham was the very first U.S. Senator to endorse Trump's third run
Speaker 194: for the presidency. As somebody who
Speaker 173 (lower-pitched voice): went
Speaker 173 (lower-pitched voice): on Carlos'
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): show weeks earlier on a similar subject, the Pentagon Personnel Wars. I'm not sure he was so much talking about like a rivalry within the cabinet as much as people that were trying to go after Wyckoff and the diplomatic approach in the media in D.C. And that was a very real thing.
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): That was a very real thing. The Foundation for Defense and
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Democracies was not complimentary, Mr. Wyckoff. Yeah, but
Speaker 196: they're delusional in like a million different ways. Yes, but they're very influential.
And
Speaker 107: they're an Israel lobby group. And they, I mean, the White House has literally, literally been caught copying and pasting from their website. Like, you know.
I
Speaker 107: mean, Trump
Speaker 79: in 2024, did I just imagine this or did I dream this? Trump in 2024, what was his criticism of Biden and Harris vis-a-vis
Speaker 133: Israel? It's that they were not subservient enough, essentially, to Israel or they were not lavish enough in their provision of munitions to Israel. He said that
And
Speaker 79: Biden and Harris were in hock to anti-Semites and
Speaker 80: they were kowtowing to Hamas and he would show them who's boss and show the world what a true pro-Israel policy was like. Did he not say that? He did
Speaker 198: both.
Did he
Speaker 199: say things to the contrary? No. Yeah, he did.
What did
Speaker 199: he say to the contrary? What did he say to the contrary?
He
Speaker 199: said he was very anti-war, so he didn't get out of all these wars, these
Speaker 200: wars would never happen.
Speaker 162: So occasionally he would throw out some meaningless
Speaker 88: platitude, but when it actually got down to brass tacks in terms of the policy, it was always an ardently pro-Israel policy. And sure enough, that much heralded ceasefire, when they come to office, Trump can get his Reagan 1981 hostage moment.
You
Speaker 201: can have the view...
Speaker 201: That was systematically
Speaker 88: undermined and Trump expedited, just as he promised to do, heavier munitions
Speaker 79: to Israel during the so-called ceasefire period and systematically undermined the ceasefire in conjunction with Israel. Didn't he do that? All right, let Kurt talk now.
You could
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): have the view that the anti-war right are suckers and they should never have trusted Trump. That's a view. Daniel
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Larrison, I think, has that view. Other people have that view. That's fine. That's fine.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): And to a large extent, that has been borne out by history. I
think it
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): is
Speaker 143 (lower-pitched voice): hilarious, though, to have that view in tandem that the Israel lobby just doesn't really matter that much.
But
Speaker 202: I've never said that. I thought I was just
Speaker 203: getting lectured for not acceding to nuance or mischaracterizing your view in the most maximal display. I've never said the Israel lobby doesn't matter.
Speaker 203: I'm saying,
Speaker 133: again, its influence has been strategically exaggerated or overemphasized, again, to exculpate Trump
because
Speaker 162: people don't want to deal with his actual worldview. You think he actually knows the first thing about William McKinley and he's like, oh, this is incredible and I want to run this
Speaker 113: extremely weird empire.
Speaker 113: I don't think he's sitting
Speaker 206: around reading dense William McKinley biographies, but he has speech writers
Speaker 33: who channel his instincts for his inaugural address, which is one of the main historical records that is going to be looked back on to explain the second Trump term, just like the infamous Bush Freedom Agenda 2005 inaugural address, right? Which is supposed to be an encapsulation of his, quote, neoconservative
Speaker 121: ideology. Trump encapsulated his ideology to some degree in the January 2025
Speaker 79: address. He chose or his speech writers chose to channel the instincts.
Speaker 79: william mckinley and then sure enough trump does start talking
Speaker 9: about how he wants to go around the world conquering these territories so i mean we're not we're not going to cast blame of any kind on the israel lobby for trump saying once he's done with iran we're going to take cuba right so how do we explain that it's just this like free-floating vague mercantilism or like should we take trump a bit more seriously at this
Speaker 79: point especially after he had four years in the wilderness to stew over his political views and maybe crystallize things.
Speaker 79: and have them mature to some degree sure and he somehow had this brilliant idea that he's going to stomp around the world overthrowing governments seizing resources and declaring himself the ruler of
as
Speaker 121: many far-flung territories as he can it's weird is that is that
is he not
Speaker 121: doing that
Speaker 207: you think he didn't betray his campaign at all you think that like everybody just imagined this this is crazy that just was no i
Speaker 79: don't not in 2024 i mean 2016 there was no record
but
Speaker 79: 2016, you did just have to discern instincts or his pundit commentary or an offhand remark that he might have made somewhere. Not with the totality of data
Speaker 9: and evidence we have by 2024, especially if he came out in public and endorsed the concept of a joint U.S.-Israeli military operation to strike Iranian nuclear facilities. He said
Speaker 208: that. I have the clip.
Speaker 143 (lower-pitched voice): okay not really sure we're debating anymore
Speaker 209: okay um i want to i want to interject here but by the way just for people listening my debate philosophy is just to let people talk as much as possible but
i spent uh
Speaker 210: without uh interrupting uh fine as it's fine i'm a grown man do you
Speaker 211: rob do you follow what the disagreement is here or yeah yeah is everybody
Speaker 143 (lower-pitched voice): confused as to what so so i i like to let people talk as much as possible but
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): i was being slightly facetious okay i got you okay
So for
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): people listening and for you guys as well, I
like
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): to let people talk as much as possible, but I'm keeping a score of various points. Kurt, here's a point. Here's a broader point.
Speaker 212: Let's even step away from Trump for a second. I actually do think, I mean, I have a little bit of an unusual perspective on presidential power because a
Speaker 79: lot of people like to point to these structural factors that guide presidential decision-making or influence it. I'm not denying that that can be a real factor. I just think that we tend to underappreciate
Speaker 33: the extent to which a president's personal ideology.
is
Speaker 33: actually, for better or worse, I would say worse, because I would prefer, if I had my way,
to have
Speaker 33: the president enjoy less unconstrained unilateral power, especially when it comes to foreign policy and warming. But like, you know,
Joe Biden had a
Speaker 33: very defined ideology that I think was...
Speaker 33: And very instructive as to why his policy was the way it was with Ukraine and also Israel, also Israel, where he actually would say he's a Zionist. Trump doesn't say that because he couldn't define Zionism.
Speaker 215: Yeah.
Speaker 214: Yeah. OK. And, you know, Barack Obama had some
Speaker 33: pretty well-defined foreign policy views. George W. Bush did to some degree, too, or at least he had a cadre around him that incubated a certain worldview.
Speaker 216: Likewise with Trump, I'm not sure what the resistance is to acknowledging that at this point. He's not some novice on the scene.
He
Speaker 111: operated in a much wider ideological space of trying to be all things
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): to all men. And that was not lost on me. I knew this in 2024 that it was a weird situation
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): where the moderates on a lot of foreign policy questions were actually for the democratic ticket and the extremists, particularly on Israel-Palestine stuff, Israel-Iran stuff. So you had the most virulent,
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): pro-israel zionist voices
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): in america who were for trump and you also had imams in michigan imams
in
Speaker 217: pennsylvania have you ever gone
Speaker 71: to israel and asked people to give you their opinion on trump it's always the most vehement religious
Speaker 16: right-wing people who are the most fervent in supporting trump to the point that they they emblazon his visage over a
Speaker 218: commemorative coin
of king
Speaker 218: cyrus yeah and
Speaker 219: i was always uncomfortable with
that
and
Speaker 218: uh because i actually
Speaker 219: broke the ministerial code in israel to endorse
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): trump i've got i've got i've got a few clarifying questions so
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): michael for you and i'm keeping score of a few very important points and and also i'll lay my cards on the table here which is that i haven't tried to dunk enough so please i um i'll lay my cards on the table here i'm
Speaker 14: somewhere i'm i'm i'm very
Speaker 209: open-minded to both your guys's view and i i want i want to be convinced one way or the other and i
The
Speaker 65 (lower-pitched voice): part of the problem is this is not like a mathematical equation. It's like Michael is
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): just emphasizing less the role of Israel here. And Kurt, you're emphasizing more. And I want to more precisely pin this down.
And I'm
Speaker 220: going to try
Speaker 221: and ask a few questions. I'll just do it right
Speaker 220: now. I'm going to return to that in a second. Michael, a
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): question for you. If...
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): trump wasn't pressured by netanyahu for over the past year to uh wage this war in
Speaker 222: iran do you think he would
have done it i'm not trying to evade the
Speaker 79: question but it's almost like a nonsense question because like we can't how could we imagine a middle east
where israel is
Speaker 33: not an appendage of u.s primacy where iran is not this bogeyman for the
Speaker 79: past five decades and
Speaker 79: I just I'm not even sure how to answer that. And
Speaker 11: also, it's
kind of
Speaker 11: counterfactual. So at the same time, yeah, of course, Netanyahu's lobbying was a
Speaker 79: significant factor. I've never denied that. I've never denied that the force of his lobbying as a factor or the domestic pro-Israel lobby in the United States is.
as a
Speaker 79: factor although i think people have gotten
Speaker 21: a little bit fuzzy in terms of what they're even defining anymore of the as the pro-israel lobby in the united states like it's not just a pack and they're like literal pack that intervenes in congressional primaries and so forth it's
much
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): more broad and loose than that in terms of what people seem
to be
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): referring to nowadays and actually
Speaker 21: even mearsheimer and walt who agree with kurt on you know jeffrey epstein they don't have any evidence but they say yeah jeffrey epstein probably was a reason why trump went to war with Iran. So I think that speaks to the limits of their
outlook
Speaker 21: on this
Speaker 133: stuff. But no,
I think
Speaker 133: it's, I don't know. I mean, if you had a less of a bulldog
as
Speaker 79: the Israeli prime minister who maybe had less of a kinship with Trump, could it have been the case
that
Speaker 80: maybe he doesn't go through with it? Look, I guess it's possible. But I also think that to the degree that Trump did succumb to the quote unquote pressure, it was in
Speaker 133: virtue of him regarding
Speaker 133: netanyahu's israel as consonant with trump's perception of how to best project american interests and power and also set about on these
Speaker 21: resource extraction quests like he had just got gotten done with in venezuela and was trying to bulldoze the europeans to acceding to in greenland and on and on and on like he literally had just declared himself the ruler
Speaker 79: Venezuela, the ultimate governing authority with ultimate veto power in Venezuela, just like he did in Gaza in October of 2024 when he struck that so-called ceasefire deal that we're told was also anathema to the, quote, neocons.
And it might be
Speaker 79: because I don't think the neocons would have been so audacious as to have Bush or Obama.
Like
Speaker 79: Rumsfeld or Romney or whomever else, McCain, declare themselves the literal sovereign governing authority in Gaza. I don't think they would have been as audacious as Trump was. The neocons tend to be a little bit more effete or a little
Speaker 100: bit more, I don't know. They like to kind of keep things more in the realm of abstraction than that where Trump just goes
Speaker 80: full bore. Yeah.
Speaker 80: Um, so, but look, I mean, if you were, if you're viewing this all through the prism of the 2024 election, fundamentally
Speaker 79: being a ideological showdown between Donald Trump on one hand and the Cheneys on the other, which is how it got set up.
Speaker 80: Yeah. In part because of the Democrats choosing to emphasize Liz Cheney, but you know, I wrote at
the time
Speaker 80: who agrees with Liz Cheney. Trump actually agrees with Liz Cheney on policy level on X, Y, and Z issue. And yes, including most prominently Iran.
Speaker 80: and Israel and even Afghanistan because Trump decided to debut in the
Speaker 79: 2024 campaign this revelation that he was never actually intending on withdrawing from Afghanistan despite the phony deal that he came up with
Speaker 80: Pompeo he was going to keep a permanent occupation force there just like Liz Cheney wanted so I don't know, maybe what I'm ultimately sort of lamenting here is a lack of journalistic discretion
Speaker 133: or something to kind of parse through these
these
Speaker 133: platitudes
Speaker 80: and the sloganeering and the propaganda so we can better inform the public. I mean, maybe it's a hokey or maybe it's old fashioned,
Speaker 223: but that's like kind of what I at least consider myself, my own brain to be most wanting to do.
Speaker 224: What's that? You're
in
Speaker 111: the opinion game.
In the
Speaker 225: opinion game. You're
Speaker 111: not writing AP copy.
Yeah, I'm
Speaker 226: not writing AP copy. I try to incorporate as much reporting as I can. But
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): you have opinions.
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): TAC is inactivist journalism. We have a perspective. The magazine was founded against the Iraq War.
Here
Speaker 179: now it's the
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Iran War. So it's not really a surprise that we're going to be against the Iran War. The magazine...
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): uh is an early supporter and platformer of the israeli lobby perspective uh so i was not surprised it was going to be a factor in our our journal i started reading in high school yeah yeah i do we're just for just
for
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): the audience
Speaker 45: um i think though would and it it's i don't want to say like it's so much your responsibility but when when
you're so
Speaker 45: confrontational about
the way
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): other people roll. So I said at the beginning of the conversation, I don't have any objection to the way that you conduct yourself and your journalism. I really don't. Long time admirer, frankly.
But I
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): think where it potentially goes a little far is the sort of, I'm not saying you're doing this, but it's implicitly sort of evangelist, which is like, other people aren't really doing this.
so
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): for for an ideological magazine sort of like paleocon flagship whatever you want to call it like tack we
sort of
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): have to assess the politics in the here and now right so like for instance i bet you're going to hesitate to give me an answer maybe i'm wrong so do you think since you i didn't think we were talking about 24 24 elections so much tonight but we are do you think that people should have voted for kamala harris
Did
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): you vote for Kamala Harris?
Speaker 229: No,
I did
Speaker 229: not. I didn't vote for either of them. And I wrote a big piece
Speaker 21: spelling out my reasoning for why.
And I
Speaker 230: had this conversation. Who did you vote for?
I wrote in a
Speaker 21: cartoon
Speaker 231: character. Fred Flintstone,
Speaker 230: actually,
Speaker 232: because I was
Speaker 231: channeling my premonition
Speaker 232: that we were all going to be hurtling into the Stone Age. And actually, Trump did just
Speaker 98: declare last night that he was going to be bombing Iran to the Stone Age. And then Hegseth repeated it. So maybe I was right with my premonition. So my
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): view...
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): uh and i've given it to people who vote third party and i've voted third party as well so i'm not critical but when i did i had a i had a very clear view and i think this is borderline
everything else is
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): kind of natal navel gazing if you vote third party
let's not say like a perot
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): 92 situation right where people
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): maybe thought he could still win or something
Speaker 233: friend flason doesn't have a party by the way it was a throwaway vote you can't serve
He
Speaker 234: can't serve.
He's
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): not a good person.
I think we agree
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): to that.
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): When you vote third party, it implies agnosticism about who wins the election. That you think both
sides
Speaker 8: are just as bad. Not necessarily.
Okay, so I find that annoying. Because
Speaker 235: like...
Speaker 27: I have critiques. I don't support either Kamala Harris or Donald Trump. And I'm not going to affirm...
Speaker 27: my
Speaker 161: i'm not going to affirm them by way of my vote it reeks of purity of purity it really does
like
Speaker 236: everybody can come up with their own rationale for why i don't evangelize for anybody to vote the way that i do i wrote my big explanation piece for why i voted the way i did
that i
Speaker 236: recognize i'm in the extreme
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): minority okay you are
welcome to
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): do whatever you want but you come after a lot of people for not thinking quite like you
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): That's
Speaker 238: not true.
Speaker 79: I'm not trying to uprate anybody who voted for Donald Trump. I don't go out in the street saying, hey, mister, did you vote for Donald Trump? If so, let
Speaker 121: me read you the riot act. It's people in the media with platforms and with political influence who contributed to propagating a false impression of the most, I think you would agree, the most important political figure of our era.
In
Speaker 143 (lower-pitched voice): 2024, who did you think, on balance, was
the
Speaker 162: better major party candidate,
Speaker 241: even if you didn't vote for them?
To
Speaker 121: me, I was agnostic as to that because on – You thought they were equally bad or equally good? I thought they were both bad
Speaker 79: for sometimes overlapping and sometimes distinct reasons. Like I wasn't going to – I wasn't going to co-sign a continuation of the Biden foreign policy status quo, but nor was I going to participate in this –
Speaker 79: reimagination of donald trump as some kind of crusader against the
Speaker 121: deep state and some anti-war person when we had so much data from the first term like i mean kurt do
Speaker 79: you think anybody should have been surprised that he tried that he successfully did regime change or regime regime altercation or modification in
Speaker 100: venezuela when he finally had the the weight of the federal government organized around him in a more structured way when he tried to do that very thing in the first term
Speaker 161: and screwed it up like was this unforeseeable
Speaker 161: I've talked to these people. He pursued parallel tracks. There was a real negotiation. Grinnell is one of his boys.
Speaker 45: That
was a
Speaker 45: real negotiation. Rubio out one. Like you implied this massive fait accompli. Yeah.
Speaker 206: If the negotiation says flee the country,
Speaker 206: forthwith or were coming in militarily that's not a reasonable negotiation that's not a jcpoa it's not
Speaker 243: negotiation just like just winning it like how many negotiates by declaring a 60-day
Speaker 244: ultimatum let kurt finish let kurt finish then michael go okay kurt okay i'm really not getting
a
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): word in edgewise here sorry it's not what grunel did in h1 of 2025 grunel who's kind of running a shadow secretary of state was shadow state department against rubio was tasked he got hostages out of Venezuela.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): There was a more diplomatic path. Venezuela was very
much
Speaker 45: a story, particularly after the 12-day war, which was the real hawkish turn of the administration, of Rubio being a better politician than Rick Grinnell, a
Speaker 45: They're cobbling together a few incentives for Trump to
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): make the decision. Number one, Trump started liking military action, reminding him that, you know, he sort of enjoyed it. Right. Which is not always salient in his mind. Number two, there is there isn't actually there's like a Latino conservative lobby. You can see that. Right. That's a real thing.
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): I was
just in
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): Miami with them.
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): Trump now lives there. Right. So I think that's actually more like he always had the house there, but he's perma there or was doing much more than he was in the first term.
Speaker 45: And then, you know, that Ruby won that out. But your analysis, like, implies that this whole sort of debate within the administration never occurred.
Now, that
Speaker 45: might not be a reason to vote for the administration. You'd be like, well, Kurt's saying is kind of pathetic.
Speaker 45: like this this had a 10 chance of working and trump is very dangerous and you shouldn't go for them but what i think is sort of interesting then i think if you think that i kind of think you should like if you think trump is so dangerous
um
Speaker 245: you think this stuff is is so off the rails i kind of think you just you should say you should go for harris well
i don't
Speaker 106: agree i
Speaker 246: mean that that wasn't my own personal calculation and i spelled this out in great detail and an essay that people can look up if they want from you know
Speaker 246: November of 2024 because especially, you know, again, this
Speaker 79: is somewhat me
in a
Speaker 79: niche journalistically, but me not wanting to almost like psychically align myself with a particular candidate unless I can proactively make an affirmative case for them, which I could not for either
Speaker 133: Trump.
or
Speaker 133: harris so that's just my own spin on what my reasoning is for my own private personal vote i don't i don't lecture anybody else
Speaker 80: to do that especially not people not especially not ordinary citizens i just think that you know if you end up coming to a like a rationale for your support if you're in the media
Speaker 133: right if you're a journalist you know okay then there's some different criteria that i'm going to be analyzing you through especially if you got a big platform and you know, if you decide that it's
Speaker 79: totally cool and, you know,
Speaker 79: justifiable to do as tucker did and outright endorse donald trump speak at the republican convention go around pennsylvania campaigning for him at campaign stops use your huge independent media audience
Speaker 80: to proselytize for donald trump and you're putting out a false image it's not just me trying to tell tucker oh you got to do exactly what i do in my own idiosyncratic way in terms of how i decide my vote it's me looking at his public output and noting that
Speaker 80: it contributed to fomenting this radically false impression of what people were getting from yes the most outsized and probably long-lastingly significant american political figure of our age that's a problem for me and i think it should be for anybody who considers themselves a rational chronicler of american politics
Speaker 125 (lower-pitched voice): i'm pro tucker but i'm not tired so like i mean okay i mean i i was
Speaker 247: too but then he starts talking about pizzagate and
Speaker 247: pizza and grape soda and like okay okay this is israel's war it's not
Speaker 80: america's war like nothing is ever trump's doing because
he loves it
Speaker 80: because he likes trump so much and i guess his son works for vance or whatever so it's like just this tangle of conflicts of interest i don't think is conducive to what i yes maybe in my slightly
Speaker 79: melodramatic way sees as my supreme prerogative which is truth seeking as best
i can
Speaker 79: rather than access preservation
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): so so
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): kurt i asked michael
If
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): Trump would have done what he's doing now in Iran without any influence from Israel and he wasn't wasn't sure he didn't really have a strong answer. Kurt, do you have a strong answer to that about what would have happened?
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): No, no way. No
Speaker 248: way. It's
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): too risky. It's too risky. It's it's it's not like people people are stretching
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): to find like, you know,
Speaker 97 (lower-pitched voice): Trump statements from the 80s where he talked about Carg Island, you know, like that is
weird.
I
Speaker 249: didn't know that until
Speaker 250: recently that he had a particular preoccupation with Karg Island. I don't
Speaker 143 (lower-pitched voice): remember him campaigning on Karg Island. So,
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): you know. No, I think it's... Look, my position is simple and I'm not so sure it's...
I think the
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): clash here is almost more aesthetic and emphasis is stylistic more than what we actually think is the truth, although I
think not
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): fully. Israel... I'm still confused. Israel set the table.
Trump
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): ate the meal. It's that
Speaker 218: simple.
Okay. So
Speaker 218: Trump might have not campaigned
specifically
Speaker 33: on Card Island, but he did campaign saying his policy from the first term on Iran was great, which included maximum pressure sanctions, maximum pressure sanctions coming within what he said was minutes of bombing Iran in June of 2019, drone assassinating Soleimani. Go look at what Tulsi Gabbard said during this time about how that was all ineluctably leading to a regime change.
Speaker 33: confrontation with Iran.
Speaker 251: And then he's also pledging in 2024 to ratchet up the bellicosity, right? So maybe not Cargill in particular, but
Speaker 121: like, yeah, Trump sets the stage. BB's there with the fork and knife. He sees that Trump's raring to go with the main course and then he gives him a nudge and you know, there you go. So like, I mean, at what point is it like Trump actualizing his own
Speaker 121: desires
Speaker 88: here is it always rubio grinnell is
it always bb
Speaker 88: outflanking i don't know who who would be his
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): nemesis i think
Speaker 45: we got the point okay okay
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): okay there was a view that trump really only cared about leaving the iran deal because of obama
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): i pretty much agree with that um
trump even in the
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): campaign actually said he wouldn't leave the iran
deal
He
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): said he opposed it, but he wouldn't leave it. It's a forgotten thing.
In
Speaker 253: 2016?
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. On one debate stage, he said he opposed the deal, but you don't necessarily need to leave the deal once we're in the deal. Of course, he retracted on that. There was a view that the populist right, the new right, whatever you want to call it, the anti-war right was thoroughly unprepared to staff an administration. And so it was staffed by hawks and neocons who fed him a bunch
Speaker 254: of-
in
Speaker 254: the first term
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): yeah no second second
Speaker 219: we're in a brave new world right supposed to be a new right being i'm trying to explain why people thought this might
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): happen so like you know and so like you know that's like designating the rgc a terrorist organization that's like sanctioning everything from the iranian space program to you know health care system
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): whatever the hell sanctioning
Speaker 255: them during covid so they could not import medical
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): supplies i'm against all of it i'm
You know, I
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): think they're not an American interest and they're inhumane. And I also think they kind of don't work with the regimes more richer in some ways today because
of the
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): war than not. But like the
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): there was a view that if
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): you if you got an improved personnel, the sort of leitmotif on on the right was, you know, the president's, you know,
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): main failure in term one was personnel. And if you got
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): different personnel in there,
and I think the
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): exemplar of this is the shift from Pence to Vance, right? I hope that Vance represented the tip of the spear of something very, very
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): different. I think what this war shows is actually the limits of personnel, especially
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): for a president like Trump, who is not making across the board administration decisions. There's almost no collaboration within the administration on decision. People found out about it from the internet.
Speaker 70 (lower-pitched voice): The people who knew about it were cable news hosts, foreigners, foreign governments, Israel, and a select coterie. And so I think what we're
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): substantively disagreeing about is why Trump is in the thrall of these people. You submit that it is like actual ideological kinship. I think it is way more
like,
His
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): political coalition is pressuring him to do it. I don't want to dwell on the gnarlier conjecture of potentially intimidation, et cetera, et cetera.
But I
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): think it's something that is plausible. And then moreover, something that we haven't discussed, maybe we should discuss more,
is the
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): sycophanty, actually, that the
Speaker 256: neocons are just really, really, really, really good at sucking up to him. Well, that's
Speaker 33: true. I mean, look at Elise Stefanik.
Speaker 33: Remember when she decided to rebrand as Ultra MAGA because she defended Trump in the first impeachment?
Speaker 98: Meanwhile, she was a protege of – was it Hudson Institute or Foundation for Defensive Democracy? It was one of the two. I think
Speaker 121: it was FDD. But all of a sudden, she can become Ultra MAGA because she can become the biggest Trump sycophant on the planet, and that's perfectly fine with Trump.
Speaker 121: But J.D. Vance is also a mega sycophant in his own way. He was in the Never Trump movement in 2016 back when I
Speaker 79: was
Speaker 33: criticizing them. He was saying, vote for Evan McMullin in 2016 because Trump is so intolerable, whereas I was opposed to the quote neocons that year, pointing to their fallacious renderings of Donald J.
Speaker 121: Trump. J.D. Vance was on the opposite side of that argument. By 2024, somehow he does this.
Speaker 121: ideological makeover where he's now representing this fledgling restraint caucus in the in the republican
Speaker 79: party right which was always a total misnomer he sorry sorry
my back he
Speaker 79: always supported uh arming
Speaker 260: ukraine including when he ran in 2022 he always supported ratcheting up i'll give you the quote it never got emphasized this this sort of uh fantasy version of him got emphasized where supposedly he was going to be you know The Liberals say he's doing
the business.
Speaker 260: getting a Putin or he's wanting to sell out Ukraine to Russia, the online right guys think, oh, this is our man. He's actually wanting to put a stop to the support for Ukraine or something like this. It was neither. And Taiwan, he's all about basically committing the United States to military action in the event of an incursion from the CCP. And then lo and behold, his sycophancy has reached
a
Speaker 260: nadir in the past couple of weeks when he reprised Dick Cheney. Congratulations, J.D., because we all were told that the 2024 election with you replacing Mike
Speaker 12: Pence as this innovative new addition to the ticket, right? You're going to do away with the old neocon Bush ways of Pence. You're going to bring new right energy to the ticket. What does J.D. Vance do like a little sycophant that he is? He goes to the
Speaker 246: cabinet meeting last week with Trump, which is like Kim Jong-un basically requiring
everybody
Speaker 246: to kiss his ass and jd vance has no problem with that and he says look look folks
Speaker 260: here's what we had here's what the president had to do what he did in iran because iran could give a dirty bomb a nuclear bomb to a terrorist like al-qaeda or isis and then blow up a marketplace either in israel or the united states i mean he wasn't that specific about it but he was reprising this whole dick cheney line from the
Speaker 260: Pre-March 2003 about the supposed threat of Saddam Hussein's nuclear proliferation to terrorists. That's J.D. Vance, who we're told was this restrainer, non-interventionist.
Speaker 261: You know what J.D. Vance is? Just like Rubio, a very skillful and intelligent politician who knows how to ingratiate himself into the mainframe of the Republican Party.
And he
Speaker 261: leveraged that. But, you know, he became friends with Don Jr. or whatever and Tucker. He leverages that
Speaker 260: to the VP pick. And, you know, Rubio did that as well in his own way. Although Rubio is probably more shrewd because the vice presidency is
Speaker 261: not as powerful as this hybrid secretary of state national security advisor thing that Rubio is going on. So maybe Rubio got the better end of that bargain.
Speaker 261: But again, there's so
Speaker 260: much foolishness that goes into these kind of self-flattering conceptions of what the Republican Party is now, what the Trump coalition is. Go look at the polling. I'm not talking about just like
Speaker 261: self-described MAGA Republicans who support
Speaker 262: the war with like staggering degrees of unanimity. Because,
Speaker 263: yeah, if you would have
Speaker 262: supported the opposite, though, if Trump is going to do it.
Speaker 263: Maybe so,
Speaker 260: but then that's relevant. But then you can't say that the MAGA coalition was always in some way some sort of repudiation of.
Speaker 260: bullish right especially look at trump if the
Speaker 261: polling numbers right now
i went back
Speaker 203: and looked at pew polling from
march of
Speaker 203: 03 it was like 90 to 93 percent of republicans supported the war okay
and they had around
Speaker 261: 50 of democrats at that time it's much lower now with democrats but it's the same number pretty much with republicans including when you when
Speaker 260: you when you when you filter for trump 2024 trump 2024 voters so what are we talking about here like when is the rethink coming.
Speaker 264: Okay, let's get Kurt in here.
I don't
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): really know We've got to call it soon But as much as I'd love to do this I'm not really sure what we're debating anymore I mean, are we And I don't mean to In the longer
Speaker 265: horizon What was being attributed to the Trump The meaning of the
Speaker 12: Trump coalition As this resurgence
Speaker 203: of a new right That was going to break from the past That was going to do away with Bush And Jeb and
I
Speaker 203: guess Marco at the time in 2016 was the idea, but he's back naturally.
Are we
Speaker 203: due for a rethink at any point in terms of like the larger prognosis
that a
Speaker 203: lot of people wanted to make? Or are we just kind of going to keep going ahead with the same like 2016 time warp analysis?
In light of
Speaker 266: events, in light of the data, in light of the evidence.
Okay,
Speaker 64: Kurt, and then the crucial piece I want to highlight from
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): all what Michael said there was Trump's hawkish statements towards Iran. Like, what was your calculation on that? Because, like, you said you're not surprised what he's doing in Iran, but you were maybe more uncertain than Michael
Speaker 267: was? I was, well,
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): okay, just
all over
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): the map. I think that this was always a possibility, a possibility I deeply feared.
i
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): think that basically you know unlike michael i'm willing to weigh
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): the tickets against each other and try to assess the merits so i thought that trump was higher risk higher reward and we are in the higher risk scenario okay i thought that trump not
unlike
Speaker 268: obama showed a greater
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): willingness for diplomacy and face-to-face sort of remember the obama debate like i'll go meet the ayatollah
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah. Same thing.
Speaker 126: Same. North Korea is an example.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): That was
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): undermined
Speaker 126: by the policy maximalism, right?
I thought
Speaker 73 (lower-pitched voice): that that was plausible. I bought into some of the personnel arguments
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): that the Republicans would be a lot more built up and in this direction. You know, the staffers in this administration...
It's
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): impossible
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): to quite quantify, but they are materially different than they were the first term. I'm not sure how relevant this is, but they are spiritually and ideologically new rightists. They like Tucker. There's different...
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): yeah
Speaker 114: based whatever i think i think it's
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): been i think it's been as
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): it's been commented by other people i think it's also having tulsi is part of his cabinet too
right
Speaker 129: yeah yeah i mean tulsi's in in you know in the job of of avril haynes right i mean it's sort of like you know how's that worked
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): out for and well and divorcing himself for mike pompeo as well right was that also part of your calculation kurt
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): what
Speaker 43 (lower-pitched voice): divorcing himself from Mike Pompeo that looked like an early win but then it was over I mean I was against Rubio getting the the secretary of state job um I think I think
Speaker 68 (lower-pitched voice): it was I think it was a close-front thing I think he considered there was that 36-hour period where he
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): announced where there was a report on it but he didn't announce it there was a sort of like huge shadow war between him and Grinnell so like I mean I don't mean to like sort of like say like oh well
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): I'm slightly more connected to like MAGA world as a reporter than Michael.
You
Speaker 270: may be. I mean, I know some people, but you may know more. There were real fights. There were real fights.
And I
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): do respect the argument that this like structurally didn't really matter. The Hawks were always favored and that Trump was always
Speaker 78: inclined in this direction. But there were fights and Trump did consider all of this. When you say he
Speaker 271: divorced from Pompeo.
what
Speaker 271: did that mean substantively he divorced from pompeo who by the way i went on the final day of
the
Speaker 12: campaign i was following trump around in pennsylvania and pompeo was giving stump speeches for trump at the trump campaign events and so was rubio i think he wanted he wanted
Speaker 272: to have the old job back so
Speaker 12: we were told we were told in 2024 that trump was getting a divorce from nikki haley and mike pompeo right so that was that was going to usher in this revolution of new right thinking
into the
Speaker 12: next administration i think
Speaker 11: the pompeo who does he appoint in lieu who does he appoint
Speaker 11: in lieu of Mike Pompeo for Secretary of State. Rubio, who's like not ideologically dissimilar from Pompeo meaningfully at all. And then instead of Nikki Haley as UN ambassador, he picked Stefanik. So it had nothing to do with the substance. It was, as so often the case with Trump, a personality
Speaker 12: soap opera thing where he doesn't really have any substantive disagreements with John Bolton for the most part, but they had a personal falling out
And
Speaker 12: then he, sure enough, appoints to succeed John Bolton as national security advisor initially, Mike Waltz, who was a protege of Dick Cheney
and
Speaker 260: who Bolton actually praised because they were in such ideological affinity with one another. So, again, go back to the substance, go back to
Speaker 35: the policy, forget the personality. Kurt, I know you got to go in a minute
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): here, but like the again, Trump's hawkish statements towards Iran on the 2024 campaign
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): trail.
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): Michael sees what he's doing now in Iran as a continuation and a rational extrapolation of what
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): he said at the time. And he did say a lot of hawkish things towards Iran. But what was your thinking at the time that maybe he's saying these things about Iran, but he's also saying we're anti-war things. So it's kind of a coin toss or
Speaker 274: negotiation bluster. I
Speaker 275: thought that they.
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): They.
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): would potentially seriously i mean i wasn't so sure the way they would approach the iran portfolio but like once he opened up the negotiations in april of last year so about this time last year when netanyahu was here and he clearly announced netanyahu's displeasure uh that negotiations were opening um what do you mean i mean to that yahoo's displeasure netanyahu came
Speaker 271: out like a kid in a candy shop when that announcement was made because netanyahu said that he and trump were in agreement that the only viable resolution, the only viable endpoint
Speaker 271: for those negotiations was Iran somehow agreeing to have the, quote, Libyan model inflicted on them?
Speaker 103 (lower-pitched voice): No, no. If you go back to the clip on that, he's not, he's visibly uncomfortable. And
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): additionally... So you're just like reading body language. Okay. All right. Let's move on from this. No, I mean, really. I mean, because, like,
Speaker 96 (lower-pitched voice): There's reporting that the Israelis did not expect that to happen, and that was not their preference.
Speaker 276: Yeah, there's been a lot of goofy reporting about some kind of fissure between Netanyahu and Trump that really hasn't been
Speaker 200: borne out in the policy systems, right? The Israelis, their preference was not negotiations. They did not want negotiations. They wanted war.
They
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): wanted this. And negotiations themselves were a detour of that.
Speaker 44 (lower-pitched voice): And as soon as the negotiations elapsed, the Israelis enforced a deadline to a negotiation that they weren't party to. Well,
Speaker 277: Trump declared the deadline. Trump declared a 60-day ultimatum in the first round before midnight happened.
Speaker 141: Right, right. But Trump has declared a lot of deadlines, and they don't usually start wars.
Speaker 277: So...
I don't
Speaker 278 (lower-pitched voice): know. That seemed like a pretty firm deadline to me. And then like when once the 60 day mark came, sure enough, the war was launched. So I don't know. I think
Speaker 279: we can make a surprise about it. And so maybe, you know, then when I spoke to
Speaker 12: Russian government officials, they're now surprised or because because they thought that Trump was actually going to magically solve the Ukraine war in 24 hours. Wasn't that part of Wyckoff's portfolio? How's that going? Can we get an update sometime?
Speaker 12: so it's just like
Speaker 129: it's very
Speaker 280: disappointing you don't need to tell me michael i want to ask you two questions in front of kurt michael i want to ask you two questions so it's
just
Speaker 12: like a kurt so after the 2016 election i spent a lot of time almost doing like a pundit media autopsy for how they screwed things up so badly tucker the first time i was ever on his show he's actually the fox and friends weekend host at the
Speaker 271: time was to talk about
a daily
Speaker 271: beast article that i wrote about
a
Speaker 271: how the media had this Trump-sized blind spot
Speaker 12: where they were missing the story in the election, they were all cloistered and insular, and they were confirmation biased, and they couldn't understand why anybody would support Trump, and et cetera, et cetera. Michael, I really want to get to two questions.
A lot of
Speaker 12: time on that.
Speaker 282: And so I think we need something like that for 2024, but there's not much of an appetite for it, which, again, is very frustrating to me.
Speaker 283: Sorry to interrupt. Michael, two questions that I want to just ask you quickly in front of Kurt. One, do you acknowledge that at least...
Speaker 283: It seems like you're not
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): acknowledging at all, but I think you would, that Trump, in addition to his more hawkish statements, he did also say a lot
of
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): anti-war things as well that Kurt was factoring in his calculation. And then secondly, I do want to ask about the, you know, Kurt said 50-50 split between, you know, Trump and Israel in the decision. I'm curious what you make
Speaker 65 (lower-pitched voice): of that or like what your calculation would
Speaker 10: be. And Trump's a very shrewd politician. He pulled off getting elected
twice, the
Speaker 10: second time non-consecutively.
Speaker 20 (lower-pitched voice): So I think we're all in agreement, or we should be, and I've always said this, that Trump is one of the most brilliant political minds ever, maybe the most brilliant political mind in American history, because like Grover Cleveland wasn't dealing with the same media environment when he got elected to two non-secondary terms. So you don't think any of his anti-war – Although I do regret that Grover Cleveland, because he's from my hometown of Kabul, New Jersey, now got – So you don't think any of his anti-war
Speaker 286: statements were –
Speaker 12: No, not really, because he would blurt out –
A
Speaker 12: platitude or a slogan or something that wasn't tied to any actual tangible policy prescription.
Speaker 271: And you have Tulsi Gabbard and RFK Jr. going around on his behalf saying utter nonsense like they did at the Madison Square Garden rally right before the
Speaker 12: election, where Tulsi Gabbard said a vote for Trump is a vote to end wars, not to start them. And RFK Jr. said voting Republican is a vote for Trump.
in
Speaker 12: 2024 is voting to "end the warfare state" as Trump wasn't bragging incredibly openly about how he did
Speaker 278 (lower-pitched voice): record-busting military budgets the first term and was going to increase them even further in the second
Speaker 287: term which he now has 1.5 trillion. So no, I mean, I don't buy that. You have to have some
Speaker 288: discernment. What is tied to actual policy prescription? What is tied to his record when he wielded power for four years? What is tied to what we can infer from his personnel choices?
Speaker 288: And then actual and then project out word in a rational way rather than just being bedazzled by him saying, oh, yeah, in the abstract, we don't like war. Who says we do like war? Both Zelensky and Putin have said for the past four years that they both don't like war. It doesn't really mean that much until you drill down to the specifics. Right. And that's what there was such a
Speaker 276: reluctance to do for some reason with Trump.
Speaker 264: Yeah.
You got to
Speaker 264: go? Okay. Mike,
do you want to
Speaker 264: stick around for another minute? I'm going to ask a couple. I'll
Speaker 289: stick around for sure if you'd like. I'm sure. I
Speaker 276: hope this was all done in good spirits.
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): Salud. Take care. Thanks, Kurt.
so
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): michael he couldn't wait to get out of there so michael the some of his more anti-war statements like when he when he was campaigning give me an example
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): hold on when he was camping yeah when he's campaigning in michigan and he was saying i'm going to stop the bloodshed in gaza i'm not going to bomb any
more
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): muslim majority countries i'm going to put an end to wars you say
Speaker 290: i'm not going
to bomb
Speaker 290: any more muslim majority countries
Speaker 290: He said something where
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): he was appealing to Muslim voters in one statement. I forget what the exact statement is. I don't want to bomb more Muslim countries, something to that effect.
But so
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): when he said, like, I want to stop the bloodshed in Gaza and I'm not going to bomb Middle Eastern countries, like you feel like that was just him selling himself to those people, but not actually sincerely believing any of that.
Well, go look with a little bit
Speaker 291: more precision about what he said.
Speaker 291: Because, you know, I mean, I'll even play the clip right now, but I actually have it.
Speaker 292: Okay.
So this is the Iman speaking in
Speaker 293: Michigan.
Thank
Speaker 294: you.
Speaker 294: to what trump said i
Speaker 295: think i think trump is in this one you might
not
Speaker 294: be in that clip
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): but oh it might not be in that but he reiterated a lot of those statements or echoed those statements himself hold on
Speaker 296: hold on i think i got like i think i think i have his quote from dear board because it's important because that's what
Speaker 297: people are
going to cite yeah sure
Here we go, here we go. Here we
Speaker 299: go.
Can
Speaker 271: I pause for a second? He says...
The
Speaker 271: Muslims in Michigan and elsewhere want to stop to the endless wars because the
Speaker 291: Republicans are smart. They have pollsters and strategists. They know that there's disenchantment with the Democrats in 2024 over Gaza and Israel policy, and they can exploit that, right? Especially in a state that's as crucial as Michigan. So what does he say? This constituency I'm trying to cater to, they want to stop to
Speaker 271: endless wars.
Speaker 271: That's a, that's a vague, that's a purposeful vagary. Okay. That's a platitude. What does that mean? Endless
Speaker 12: wars. Did you notice last night in speech about the Iran war, he's contrasting it with wars that he would call maybe endless wars like Iraq and, uh,
Speaker 276: or Korea even brought up, um, he actually didn't say Afghanistan for some reason. Uh, he did say Iraq. Iraq.
Speaker 276: And, um, and
so that's
Speaker 271: sort of like baked into the rationale that they're putting forth for why this war is something that everybody should support because it seemed to be this like decisive deployment of a brute force American power in contrast with quote nation building or whatnot. Although it should be said that Trump now, Trump explicitly declared that he's going to be nation building in Gaza. He actually used that term. Um, so.
Speaker 260: And so, again, it's very easy to say, oh, we don't like endless wars in the abstract. I think Barack Obama said stuff to that effect. I think even Joe Biden would say stuff to
Speaker 271: that effect and probably did. I'm sure Kamala would have said stuff to that effect. It doesn't really matter in terms of the...
Speaker 271: relevance for actual policy unless you can tie it to a firm policy prescription otherwise it's a nice sounding platitude that you could see the political rationale for right
Speaker 260: which is why i am just very disappointed to say the least with people who are in the media or in journal like they're supposed to be covering american politics with a critical journalistic lens hearing that
stuff
Speaker 271: and just saying to them say saying to themselves oh gee that must be be he'm running on an anti-war platform
and
And
Speaker 271: we're not going to look at the record from the past from four years when he had power the first time. We're not going to look about the personnel. We're not going to like even analyze it for how connected it is or not to any kind of tangible policy prescription because
Speaker 12: it simply wasn't because he was simultaneously.
Speaker 12: saying on a firm, tangible policy level to the pro-Israel hardcore faction
like
Speaker 271: Miriam Adelson and Tom Cotton and Rubio and all these other people that he was going to carry forth his policy paradigm
from the
Speaker 271: first term when he brags that he was the most pro-Israel president ever, and if not for him, Israel would have been destroyed. He's going to do that same
Speaker 246: thing in a second term, and yeah, that does bear on Iran. So
Speaker 261: I'm
Speaker 260: going
Speaker 12: to
show you a little bit more.
I
Speaker 246: think a discerning mind, especially if you're like a journalist,
Speaker 261: right? I'm not just talking about an average citizen who has a job and stuff and like a family and can't spend all day pondering this stuff.
Speaker 301: Yeah, you
Speaker 260: should be. You should be able to use a bit more some exactitude to not just say, oh,
Speaker 12: we're going to give equal weight to him going to Dearborn and pandering to these imams with these slogans.
Speaker 12: As we do what is in the record as to what the policy prescriptions would be.
Speaker 260: Because even when he says we want to put an end to the war in Gaza, right?
He would
Speaker 11: always say. Look, he would always denounce the Biden administration for not sending munitions as aggressively as they should have
Speaker 271: to Israel for the purpose of finishing the job in Gaza, meaning pulverizing Gaza harder and faster so that we can end it. It wasn't like, oh, we're going to
wave a...
we're
Speaker 271: going to extend an olive branch and wave a white flag or, you know, and then like declare that peace is broken out. And that's exactly what he did when he then got into office. Like when they had that Whitcoff so-called ceasefire, they took the opportunity, Trump took the opportunity, Trump and Rubio to expedite the heavy munitions to Israel that they, they whined that Biden didn't send profligately enough, even though Biden ironically
Speaker 260: had sent more munitions to Israel
than,
than any
Speaker 260: U.S. president ever. But for the Republicans and Trump,
that
Speaker 11: wasn't enough. And Trump also elevates hardcore religious fanatics who would have
been
Speaker 260: uncouth even to so-called neocons of the past,
like
Speaker 271: McCain or Romney or even George W. Bush.
You
Speaker 291: wouldn't
Speaker 271: have seen George W. Bush with
Speaker 291: Hegseth as his so-called war secretary. I should have asked Kurt, oh, did Israel trick Trump?
and
Speaker 291: Hexeth into doing this weird rebranding
Speaker 302: thing of the defense department where now it's the war department and Hexeth is the war secretary.
Speaker 260: He doesn't indicate anything about their Fred elections. So, so no, I mean, again, you, you, you, you are, you
Speaker 246: are very suspiciously lacking in political wisdom and judgment. If you took that, those offhand comments in Dearborn as
to
Speaker 246: be given equal weight
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): to the much more fulsome breadth of evidence that showed what Trump's actual policy in the Middle East would be.
Speaker 303: Okay. So do you think he's not
in any
Speaker 303: meaningful
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): way less hawkish than the neocons like Lindsey Graham or Mark Levin or any of these people? I don't know what neocon means
Speaker 204: anymore.
Speaker 12: I don't know what neocon means anymore. It's an obsolete term. Seriously, after the 2024 election, when he nominates Rubio and Hegseth and so forth, I wrote a whole essay.
Speaker 12: look it up is donald trump a neocon
and i
Speaker 12: might i said and my answer was to the rhetorical like semi-ritoral question
Speaker 271: was no because neocon is not a relevant term anymore in as of 2024 definitely as of 2026 right because
Speaker 271: Look, there was a faction of actual neoconservatives in the late 90s and early 2000s that got very fixated on foreign policy, some
Speaker 291: of whom were sort of the ideologues of the first Bush administration, like Paul Wilfowitz, Douglas Feith, Richard Perle, etc.
So by
Speaker 271: 2024, neocons came to be a pejorative term that would get slapped on anybody who one didn't like and also perceived them to have overly hawkish foreign policy views, which is like not really that well connected to like what would it.
Speaker 271: It would have meant to be a neoconservative ideologically. So if Trump is appointing Rubio as the person who's best equipped and most compatible with him to carry on his foreign policy agenda, and
Rubio would
Speaker 271: have been seen as the arch neoconservative
in the
Speaker 271: U.S. Senate, right alongside Lindsey Graham
for his
Speaker 271: entire career, essentially,
then
Speaker 271: how is trump not a neoconservative himself so my conclusion was let's get do away from this lazy handicapping term which doesn't which which which obscures nowadays more than reveals and just describe what trump is neoconservative no he's got his own ideology that i think is somewhat distinct from like a george w bush ideology or at least what george w bush and his cohort avowed um
In
Speaker 271: some ways, that means Trump's ideology is more extreme in its military bellicosity because there
was also an
Speaker 271: Israel lobby under Bush.
There
Speaker 12: was also lots of people who wanted to attack Iran under Bush because they
Speaker 246: claimed that there was an imminent nuclear threat. Bush never went along with that. Cheney, I think, advocated for it within the administration, if memory serves, but that never happened. Bush would never have declared himself the ruler of Gaza, really, the ruler of
Venezuela, taken
Speaker 246: over at Greenland.
Speaker 271: That would not have been in Bush's repertoire. So Trump's got his own distinct ideological features. Yes, that stems in part from his personality, his temperament, his fixation on resource extraction, because he denounced Bush for not taking the oil in Iraq. It wasn't so much invading Iraq, although he said that was probably a bad idea. It was that once you invaded, you should take the oil and Bush couldn't do it. So you think
Speaker 304: he's more hawkish
than Bush?
It's a
Speaker 261: spectrum, it's like a multi-dimensional spectrum almost I think in certain ways, Trump is more cavalier About the exertion of American coercive force abroad Like, I don't think, I have a hard time
Speaker 203: thinking of Bush Coming up with the idea to just start bombing random boats In the Caribbean Sea for a couple of months As he amasses the biggest naval armada In the history of South America Off the coast of
Speaker 261: Venezuela Thank you.
Speaker 261: Like, that's probably not something that Bush would have come up with. It doesn't necessarily mean that Bush wasn't, quote, hawkish, right? It
just
Speaker 12: means that there are different strains
of, quote, hawkish
Speaker 12: American power projection, some of which are distinct to Trump, some of which are distinct to Bush. Like, we don't have to be constantly stuck in this frame
Speaker 271: where we're always comparing and contrasting stuff to, quote, neocons circa 2003. I mean, it's been over two decades, right?
So let's update our priors as to how we're understanding
Speaker 271: the...
Speaker 271: spectrum of american foreign policy views and the the ideologies that exist within it especially given that trump has been the paramount american political figure for the past 11 years so that he he's going to remake things in his image to
some extent
Speaker 271: neocon becomes just this buzzword that people can throw out to kind of like counterpose trump with counterpose mago with even when it doesn't really mean anything i mean all the actual neocons like a lindsey ram
they
Speaker 271: just re updated their branding or rebranded themselves and fully ingratiated into the Trump, the Trump orbit. Like when Trump was out of office in 2022, I went to the opening sort of conference of the
Speaker 291: America first policy Institute, which was basically the think tank
Speaker 291: waiting to become the second Trump administration while he was out of office. It was run by Howard Lutnick, who then became the committee, the transition chairman, and then the commerce secretary and Lyndon McMahon, who was the small business administrator in the first term
Speaker 271: and is now the education secretary. Right. And they were, they were incubating the personnel and the staff for the next Trump administration. And
they,
And that's
Speaker 271: where people like Mike Waltz, guys like Mike Waltz would go and say, we got to win in Ukraine. We actually have to send American
forces in some form
Speaker 271: to help Ukraine fire missiles correctly into Russia. I mean, I interviewed him at the time. Like Joni Ernst would go and make the most bellicose statements you could imagine. Lindsey Graham, I think, was there as well. Pompeo, Newt Gingrich, et
Speaker 12: cetera. Like all was welcome under the MAGA umbrella or the American.
Speaker 12: America first umbrella. And so that became the prevailing Republican party branding in the Trump era. Right. So in
light of that, you got to
Speaker 12: be a little bit more discriminating
in terms
Speaker 12: of what we're calling hawkish or not. If our reference point for what is hawkish is still stuck in the George W. Bush era. Okay. What about forever wars?
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): Right. Trump has explicitly said I oppose forever wars. Could
Speaker 306: that
be what
Speaker 306: does that mean? Barack Obama said that Joe Biden said that Joe Biden actually ended one of the
Speaker 306: quote unquote forever wars
Speaker 271: afghanistan and for his efforts had denunciation after denunciation flying his way from the republicans and
trump
Speaker 307: himself for
Speaker 271: withdrawing from afghanistan now they'll say oh it was just the manner in which they executed the withdrawal
Speaker 291: that was always a fallacy because the idea that you're ever going to do a totally
seamless withdrawal
of a
Speaker 291: long-term U.S. military occupation in South Asia, or Central Asia, rather.
That was
Speaker 271: absurd. So the Republicans basically came out and opposed the withdrawal almost on principle,
even if they
Speaker 271: would claim that it was about the execution. Then Trump, sure enough, revised his entire purported view on Afghanistan and started saying in 2024 that
he was
Speaker 271: never going to withdraw at all from Afghanistan, even though he
Speaker 12: and Pompeo,
had
Speaker 12: nominally brokered what was called the Doha agreement with the Taliban to withdraw all U.S. troops from all U.S. bases in Afghanistan after X number of years or X number of conditions were met. Well, lo and behold, we learned from Pompeo and
Speaker 246: Trump that the conditions
were never
Speaker 246: going to be met by design, right? So they were going to keep a permanent occupation force in Afghanistan. They claim it was so they could have a base that was somehow proximate to China and Chinese nuclear
Speaker 11: facilities or something. But,
Speaker 11: But forever wars, that's the number one forever war, right? That was 20 something years, right? Nearly 20 years. And Trump
Speaker 261: saying he was not in favor of ending that. In fact, he agreed with Liz Cheney that
there should
Speaker 261: have been no withdrawal. So even in the abstract
Speaker 260: forever wars, nobody would come out and affirmatively support that. It doesn't mean anything. Right.
What
Speaker 12: does that mean that you don't, that you think in hindsight, maybe it wasn't a great idea to invade Iraq? Okay. I mean, if people think that that's now some really brilliant political
Speaker 260: insight, then I think the bar is pretty low. And also, I don't know, could a war be objectionable without being, quote, forever?
Perhaps, like if you have an
Speaker 261: objection to what's going on with Iran now, it hasn't yet
gone on
Speaker 261: for forever. And also when Bush invaded Iraq, which by the way, Trump was still like basically just a celebrity pundit at the
time.
He
Speaker 203: kind of, sort of, supported it when he talked to Howard Stern, like, a few months prior, and then by 2004, yeah,
he was
Speaker 203: ahead of the curve among Republicans and came out in opposition
to
Speaker 261: it, essentially.
But in
Speaker 261: 2003, when, you know, March 19th, 2003, Bush announces the Operation Iraqi Freedom, he didn't say, oh, hey, everybody, this is
a forever war, okay?
Like, get on
Speaker 261: board. It should be awesome to have a forever war. That's not
how these
Speaker 261: things are framed. Maybe the Saran thing does become a forever war. Trump says that his intention is to personally control the
Speaker 308: Strait of Hormuz. Explain to me how that's going to be effectuated without a continuous military presence of some kind. He
says that
Speaker 308: he's going to determine...
Speaker 308: who the next political leadership is of Iran after he killed the supreme leader and after he and Israel have killed all these top rating officials. He says he's going to do just like he's been doing, just like he declared for Venezuela, and he's going to have ultimate veto power over who the political leadership is in Iran. Is that going to not entail some U.S. military presence for maybe longer than might be?
Speaker 308: people might assume if he's going to take the oil as he says he now as he says he's going to do like i can't i said the minute he launched this thing on february 28th what you think trump is
just going to do
Speaker 308: an about face and no longer be interested in taking the oil once he's done with iran
but
Speaker 309: he's come
out
Speaker 308: and explicitly said it that he plans on you know as the you to the victor goes the spoils he's going to be quote taking the oil somehow in in
Speaker 308: How is that going to be effectuated? You don't think there's going to need to be some sort of U.S. military facilitation of that? So for all we know, this could be a forever war, even though they keep saying, oh, just wait another two or three weeks. Like every two weeks,
Speaker 12: they say, give it another two or three weeks. So, of course, it's never going to be branded as
Speaker 11: a forever war. That's something that gets us. That's something that's a label that gets applied years in
Speaker 288: hindsight to a war that has become unpopular.
Speaker 288: So you don't
Speaker 310: think Trump in any scenario or situation or as part of
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): his overwhelming philosophy is anti-intervention or skeptical of intervention in any way? Are there no examples of that? Can
you hear me,
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): by the way? Yeah. Okay. Look, I mean,
in
Speaker 291: 2016, you can go find a column or several things that I wrote,
but I
Speaker 291: remember one column in particular in the New York Daily News.
Speaker 291: where I sort of sketch out how, based on
Speaker 271: the instincts that he's exhibited,
because remember,
Speaker 271: in 2016,
Trump was a
Speaker 271: novelty candidate. He had no governing record.
He was the
Speaker 271: first candidate since Wendell
Wilkie, I
Speaker 271: believe, in 1940,
to become a
Speaker 271: major party nominee without a record in government or a record in the military.
So all
Speaker 271: we had to go on as of 2016 was this sort of like rolling punditry thing that he did. And
he was a
Speaker 271: reality TV show host. He was a beauty passion proprietor. We couldn't use the same like heuristics to analyze his political worldview.
Speaker 271: As we would for a Hillary Clinton, right, who was Secretary of
Speaker 12: State, United States Senator, etc.
And so I
Speaker 12: wrote in this column that, look, I mean, Trump has some discernible instincts that suggest he goes a bit against the prevailing consensus in the Republican Party, and perhaps even to some extent in the Democratic Party, as to military interventionism.
And when you
Speaker 12: contrast that with Hillary Clinton, the contrast
is actually
Speaker 12: pretty clear.
Speaker 271: salient because Hillary Clinton in 2016 was calling for a no-fly zone to be imposed in Syria. Trump said no. Now,
Speaker 12: so those were some forward-looking projections that I made and
as
Speaker 12: to what Trump could
Speaker 271: potentially do once he's in office. But by 2024, right, I'm refusing to stay stuck in quicksand in 2016 with the mountains of data that
we
Speaker 311: gathered
Speaker 271: since then. So you
Speaker 303: don't think he's tone restrained in any scenario? Like
Speaker 312: which scenario?
Well,
Speaker 303: yeah, I'm asking, is there any scenario in your view?
Speaker 313: You think he's been hawkish on everything?
Speaker 271: I mean, he's carried forth the basically the status quo of the Biden administration when it comes to Ukraine, and he's
Speaker 291: actually loosened some of the restrictions on Ukraine for long range missile strikes into Russian territory. He's come up with a way to circumvent Congress. They don't have to make these big, politically sensitive appropriations anymore to keep arming Ukraine in perpetuity.
Speaker 291: um he got elon musk somehow recently or maybe elon did it independently i'm not sure but to basically give ukraine a leg up against russia by allowing them to access starlink and they it was cut off for russia or something to that effect so in february of 2026 ukraine actually had the first net gains in terms of territory in the
war uh than
Speaker 291: that they had since 2023 under trump um
I
Speaker 291: don't know, he's calling for record-busting military budgets, $1.5 trillion in just the yearly annual appropriation for the Pentagon. On top of that, another $175 billion from the so-called Big Beautiful Bill, his signature domestic legislation from summer
Speaker 246: of last year. And now the Pentagon's putting out an extra, on top of all that,
Speaker 261: $200
Speaker 203: billion supplemental for military spending. So,
i
Speaker 203: don't know does that suggest to
Speaker 291: you some conflict between trump and the so-called military industrial complex don jr is running some kind of like drone acquisition company
Speaker 261: now that's like in bed with pentagon uh contractors um where has he shown restraint did he
Speaker 65 (lower-pitched voice): show restraint funny by the way just like one thing which which i i recognize your point that this is all just you know very um savvy political campaigning but in uh i think right after trump got elected Um...
Speaker 65 (lower-pitched voice): putting aside your feelings on on some of these people but like dave
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): smith tweeted out something about we need more anti-war people in this administration and don jr quote tweeted it was like hell yeah something to that effect like yeah like we're gonna have anti-war people
Speaker 315: in but now don't we're gonna
Speaker 260: swap out pompeo and hailey for rubio and stefani that's what happened
yeah um but like tell
Speaker 12: me where he's shown restraint i mean oh there are instances i'm
Or there
Speaker 291: isn't plenty to criticize in terms of his foreign policy record. But Obama, when there was a big clamor, yes, in part
Speaker 12: from the Israel lobby in 2013 for him to bomb Assad in Syria as retribution for an alleged chemical weapons attack.
Obama said,
Speaker 300: look, I
believe
Speaker 12: that we probably I believe that we
Speaker 246: probably should go forward with this and bomb Assad, but I'm going
to put this
Speaker 246: to Congress.
Meaning
Speaker 12: I want congressional approval before we actually go and take military action against Syria. Congress does not approve it. And Obama aborts the mission and they come up with a diplomatic resolution in terms of with Russia, actually, in terms of transferring over some of
Speaker 246: these chemical weapons stockpiles, something roughly like that. I'm not going to have all the full details at the top of my mind. I don't know. That could be said to show restraint.
But
Speaker 11: Trump, when he gets in in 2017, he's.
He
Speaker 11: doesn't bother going to Congress. Are you kidding? They haven't even made
Speaker 12: a pretense of trying to argue that this current war is legally authorized at all with Iran. But in April 2017,
he bombs Assad without thinking
Speaker 12: twice when a similar episode happens in terms of a purported
Speaker 271: chemical weapons attack. So who showed restraint there, Obama or Trump? And then April 2018, Trump does it all over again with Assad.
Did he
Speaker 271: show restraint when he tried to do regime change in Venezuela in January of 2019? Because
he just
Speaker 271: did it in a more muscular way in the
Speaker 291: second term. So where's the restraint? The one exception has always been the North Korea negotiations. Because if you remember, in the first year and a half or so of the first Trump administration, Trump was doing maximalist rhetoric. Like he was saying, look out for fire and fury, meaning it was actually sort of
a nuclear
Speaker 291: crisis
Speaker 12: that
Speaker 246: he was fomenting.
It
Speaker 246: didn't get to that point, although Hickseth was on TV on Fox saying, yeah, just go forward with it, bomb North Korea. But
then he
Speaker 316: does
Speaker 246: this fairly unique personal
Speaker 291: diplomacy with Kim Jong-un, where he goes to Hanoi, and he even does the ceremonial step over the border from South Korea to North Korea.
Speaker 291: He's like, you know, pretty amazing photo ops of Trump and Kim Jong-un, which you never would have thought would happen.
So I
Speaker 291: was sort of on principle in favor of that, just in terms of the direct personal diplomacy. But then it was conjoined with maximalist policy demands that were never going to be resolvable by
an
Speaker 271: actual negotiation. And then the negotiations or the diplomatic contacts with North
Speaker 12: Korea fell apart. Nothing ever came of it.
Speaker 12: Right. Because they were demanding total denuclearization of North Korea, basically national humiliation and capitulation, just
like what
Speaker 12: they were demanding with Iran.
And then, you
Speaker 12: know, Kurt says, oh, look, but they came in like this was not a foregone conclusion. It could have gone either way. Whitcoff, his, you know, his boy comes out and says the only acceptable resolution for us over the course of these alleged negotiations was.
A very
Speaker 12: similar kind of national capitulation and humiliation where they would have to, where they would have to,
Speaker 11: where Iran would have to accede to total
abolition of any nuclear
Speaker 11: enrichment and effectively destroying their own nuclear facilities. Like that's what Trump was saying that they wanted in tandem with Israel. So-
Speaker 12: It was a it was a it was a pantomime of negotiations who set the groundwork for the eventual military
Speaker 271: action, which Trump very nicely previewed for us when he was running and saying, look, they tried to assassinate me. I want to blow them to smithereens. He
didn't seem like he was
Speaker 271: kidding when he said that. Oftentimes, he does seem like he's kidding or sarcastic. That was a written statement that
he came out
Speaker 12: and read. He wasn't just spitballing. OK, but.
So, I
Speaker 11: don't know, give me an area where he's shown some measure of restraint I just don't see it They tore up the arms control treaties in the first term with Russia So the
Speaker 271: INF Treaty, the Intermediate Missile Range Treaty The Open Skies Treaty And there was one more that I think I'm forgetting But the INF Treaty was the most consequential one And so Biden comes in
Speaker 271: And then Trump and Pompeo are, as he's leaving office in like late 2020, early 2021, saying, look, we're not sure if we even want to renew the New START
Speaker 291: Treaty. Like this is the, basically just the continuation of the longstanding bilateral nuclear arms control regimen that had been ongoing between the United States and the Soviet Union and later the Russian Federation since the early 70s.
Trump was
Speaker 291: threatening to just withdraw from that as
he's leaving
Speaker 271: office in the first term.
But
Speaker 271: then he loses. I mean, he'll never admit that he lost, but he did lose the 2020 election. He left office. Biden comes in. One of the first things he does is re-up the New START treaty that Trump was threatening to withdraw from.
But it's only for a couple
Speaker 291: of years, right? So the expiration date for that New START treaty renewal was like, I think it was February 4th of this year.
Trump let
Speaker 291: it expire. There was no longer any nuclear arms control regimen.
Speaker 291: bilaterally between the United States and Russia for the first time since Richard Nixon was president.
So
Speaker 11: give me an area where he's exercised this restraint. I just don't see it. People want to say, oh, he exercised restraint because he manufactured a phony crisis in June of 2019 where he was going to bomb Iran because of a ticky-tack
Speaker 260: incident where an unmanned aerial drone of the United States was allegedly shot down over the Persian Gulf, not over the Gulf of Mexico,
or
Speaker 260: the Gulf of America, not over the San Francisco Bay or the Hudson River, the Persian Gulf, Trump says, oh, I'm 10 minutes away from bombing Iran over that.
And then he holds back at
Speaker 260: the last second, decides not to do it.
And then he
Speaker 260: gets credit for restraint for why should why was he even in that position to begin with?
Speaker 318: yeah yeah i mean you gotta give
Speaker 260: me an example at some point yeah um because i i'm just not really seeing it i mean look is it
Speaker 319: possible that if you had a really hardcore like resistance democrat in office
Speaker 203: right now who had been radicalized about russia going back to russiagate and about you know how freedom was on the line in ukraine
Speaker 203: Maybe they would be expending more of
Speaker 22 (lower-pitched voice): their energies on Ukraine and maybe going a bit further in terms of trying to do – there was basically in the early stages of the Ukraine war, 2022 to roughly 2023, there was basically a policy consensus that was sort of haphazardly coalescing toward the imposition
of
Speaker 246: some kind of regime change in Russia. They had conferences in D.C. that members of Congress would attend about dismembering the Russian Federation.
I don't think
Speaker 11: that's really quite what Trump is interested in, although it should be said that he brags that he threatened to bomb Putin's personal living
quarters in his
Speaker 11: first term.
Speaker 260: Oh, really? Have you heard about that? No. Interesting what stuff gets emphasized and what stuff doesn't, right? Yeah. So, you know,
Speaker 271: in other words, it's possible that there could be something
more
Speaker 246: belligerent going on right now vis-a-vis Ukraine under a Democrat than Trump.
There
Speaker 246: is right now under Trump
and
Speaker 321: the
Speaker 246: Republicans, but pretty much it's policy
Speaker 271: status quo. And in fact, he's gone further than
Biden did
Speaker 271: with these long range missile strikes and intelligence sharing for
for for
Speaker 246: bombing missions into Russian into the Russian Federation. So I don't know. Look, I mean, it's not only not everything
is
Speaker 12: black or white. There could be a particular instance
where he
Speaker 12: does exercise some more restraint than maybe others would have liked to see.
where
Speaker 12: I've been advocating North Korea in the first term is definitely the top example of that that I've long cited. But I don't see something akin to North Korea, that North Korea exception happening in the second term, do you? And
if you do
Speaker 12: think that there's an area where he's exercised restraint, explain it to me and then we can discuss it. I'm just not seeing it on the menu right
Speaker 322: now.
Is he
Speaker 322: exercising
Speaker 12: restraint by saying he wants to seize Greenland? He wants to take over Cuba?
Speaker 306: He wants to seize the
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): oil of Venezuela? Et cetera. You are making a highly persuasive factual case, but I'm also out of
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): my expertise here in this area. I feel like we've really exhausted this, and I really appreciate your insights into this. I can go all night. I would love to pair you up in some more debates on this because I'm learning a lot from you. I learned a lot from Kurt. I
Speaker 60: will show you the zero-hedge debate that,
i
Speaker 60: agreed to do in september i think it was or october of 2024 when they paired
Speaker 302: me with
this guy from info wars which
Speaker 323: you know i wasn't really thrilled about debating because like i like to remain anchored in some degree of reality but i
did it anyway no
Speaker 323: no it was like one of his minions harrison
Speaker 324: smith oh and for oh i don't know harrison
Speaker 323: smith
Speaker 291: one of his minions okay and his point was that trump is going to trump is going to
Speaker 291: storm into office and put a stop to the greater israel project he's actually secretly anti-israel that was his
Speaker 309: point and
that's
Speaker 291: why you should vote for some okay interesting so okay
Speaker 209: yeah can we
get an
Speaker 209: update on that yeah yeah um can you can you just very quickly i know you love giving long explanations which i love but i do want to
Speaker 327: wrap this up i'll keep it short
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): kurt kurt said 50 50 i didn't want to get
if
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): you know obviously this you can't really quantify this but i'm assuming you're more like 80 20 of like this is 80 trump's
Speaker 14: doing maybe 10 20 is that sort of your thinking on this
so i mean like
Speaker 14: trump versus israel
Speaker 290: who's doing is it that the war in iran is going on
look i mean the
Speaker 302: the united states is still the reigning superpower in the world the most The powerful military, the biggest economy.
Speaker 302: Etc. The United States President is the most powerful figure On earth for better or worse
So that's
Speaker 329: where the Power dynamic Starts with me
Speaker 307: Even
Speaker 246: if As an adjunct to That projection of American hegemonic Power you have Israel in the Middle East Which is like a mini America
Speaker 291: Where that's how people characterize It when they want to say that Israel and the United States have these integrated interests
And
Speaker 291: Trump Trump subscribe to that world that
Speaker 246: belief. So, no, I just don't think you think it's
Speaker 331: marginal.
Speaker 260: It doesn't happen without the agency of Trump. OK, you can have Israel for something. Kurt would agree. Yeah. OK,
but but
Speaker 260: Trump. I'm sorry, but Obama somehow
Speaker 319: managed to thwart the Israel lobby.
In
Speaker 319: doing the JCPOA in the second term or the Iran nuclear deal, Netanyahu himself and the Israeli political class and all the lobbying groups bitterly opposed it to the point that – and I know I'm going on longer than I promised I would. I'll wrap up. The point where
Speaker 261: Netanyahu was invited by the congressional Republicans to give a speech – deliver a joint – an address to a joint session of Congress in vain against –
the
Speaker 261: sitting president's signature foreign policy initiative. Okay. But it got through anyway
Speaker 319: because Obama actually exerted the political will necessary to get his initiative enacted.
So
Speaker 300: that's why
Speaker 319: I sort
of blanch
Speaker 319: at this idea that the Israel lobby is always insurmountable and it has
this like
Speaker 319: mythical influence that like everything just, you know, they're like, Netanyahu is like, you know, playing,
you
Speaker 319: chess on the chess board and like trump is the one of the pieces and he's like moving trump along okay so if i but i but if i had to just buy into the premise
Speaker 260: and quantify it i would say
i'll go 90 10 90
Speaker 260: 90 90
Speaker 332: trump 10 yeah so
Speaker 333: how's that yeah
Speaker 333: Yeah, that's what I inferred from what you said. Although I will
Speaker 277: be pedantic and kind of reject that it can be quantified in that way. But if I'm forced to, I'm going to go 90-10.
Speaker 333: Yeah, well, yeah, of course. Okay, there's more we can still talk about here, but I feel like we've got to wrap up.
Speaker 12: Explain to me, hold on a second, if it was, let's say it was 100% Israel, 0% Trump, how would that have worked?
Speaker 12: like what would Netanyahu like
he
Speaker 122: would hypnotize the US military and deploy them himself
Speaker 264: like it doesn't even make sense that wouldn't have worked yeah yeah that's a fair point alright
Speaker 209: thanks for I feel like we can talk more about this and I would like to at some point I'll let you know it seems like the
Iran
Speaker 13: situation might be going on for a bit
longer so
Speaker 65 (lower-pitched voice): I'm sure there'll be plenty of time for debates one interesting idea actually I had which I guess I can just float by you on air here You know,
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): there's been all these
divisions
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): visions within mega land uh and one of the ones has been you know ben shapiro on one side and then all you know tucker candace megan kelly dave smith on the other side i wonder
Speaker 334: it's a soap opera i
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): i wonder you know given that ben had you on because you guys seem to agree on epstein and you guys had a friendly exchange there i wonder if ben would might be inclined to debate you on iran given that there's some there's
a
Speaker 335: level of um mutual I
don't know.
Speaker 335: respect there.
And I
Speaker 335: assume...
Speaker 88: Because
Speaker 271: I'm not a guy who says, oh, my views on Epstein have to be dictated by my pre-existing views on Israel. I'm just going to graph my Israel critical views onto Epstein arbitrarily. And then, therefore, because I'm not an
Speaker 88: Epstein maximalist, that must mean
Speaker 88: that um pro-iran war i mean this doesn't even make any sense if you think about
Speaker 336: it for two seconds but you but i assume you're you you like you think that ben is like i haven't
Speaker 337: followed the commentary on the iran war i'm sure i know what i'm sure i know
Speaker 53 (lower-pitched voice): what his position is yeah you're you're less hawkish than ben right he's more
Speaker 338: i've never been in favor of any war
like
Speaker 338: ever literally
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): yeah so yeah so so there would be tremendous amount of daylight between you and
ben i
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): would assume
so on
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): the iran war and you'd be open to a debate on that sure yeah because i feel like ben he sees um well i mean according to ben he's offered he's a hardcore
Speaker 340: pro israel i mean that's always been sort of
like the
Speaker 340: nexus of my disagreement with him going back years
yeah
Speaker 51: yeah um but yeah ben but by point i would actually
Speaker 203: praise him because he supported trump ardently as well
And I
Speaker 203: think he actually did so for rational reasons, meaning that he saw Trump as a vehicle through which his preferred policies would get enacted. Whereas you have this other crowd of like
a Dave Smith
Speaker 340: or whomever who confabulated this alternate universe understanding of Trump,
who as though
Speaker 340: he was going to be a vehicle for what they were. You can't have both.
Speaker 340: It's either
Speaker 203: Ben Shapiro or the Dave Smith-Tucker crowd, right? And it was very manifestly always Ben Shapiro
if
Speaker 308: you had to pick one in terms of the likelihood and the evidence, right? So I would commend Ben Shapiro at least for some consistency in that sense.
Speaker 341: Yeah, although you could – this is
kind of a – I
Speaker 341: don't even know how to articulate this.
Speaker 209: But you could make a case for –
Speaker 209: okay, he's at least
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): appealing to anti-war sentiments very strongly while also being hawkish and maybe if we support him and he does these big podcasts and we're all anti-war
we
Speaker 209: can hold him accountable and we can appeal to that side, we can be a moderating
Speaker 342: force. It was so
Speaker 343: stupid though because if that's your logic you're almost better off supporting and you're most concerned about Israel
in the
Speaker 343: Middle East
you're better off
Speaker 343: with a democratic coalition at this point
The
Speaker 343: Democratic coalition is
Speaker 271: not dominated by end times apocalyptic Christian believers who think that Jesus is going to come and rule over the earth from Jerusalem.
Speaker 335: Fair, but they didn't appeal at all to the anti-war independent podcast group. What do you mean they didn't appeal?
Speaker 288: Kamala didn't appeal to
Speaker 335: that at all. I'm
Speaker 288: saying if you have a rational—I'm not saying who appealed or didn't. The Kamala campaign was terrible. I said that at the
Speaker 301: time. I'm
Speaker 288: saying if what you're
Speaker 203: saying is, oh, I'm going to support a candidate and then try to influence them.
Or I'm
Speaker 203: trying to try to steer them toward my preferred ends. And you're concerned mostly about Israel, meaning or trying to have
Speaker 344: a less interventionist or pro-war take on what the proper relationship between the U.S. and
Speaker 345: Israel should be. You're better off doing that from within the Democratic Party coalition. But
again, there was
Speaker 346: at least... That's why Netanyahu
Speaker 345: has always been supportive of Republicans. He opposed Obama and
he supported
Speaker 345: Romney. He supported Trump.
But
Speaker 347: at least there was something to work with With Trump in some of his anti-war Sloganeering
Speaker 222: Whereas Kamala didn't do Again, you're acknowledging Trump did say some anti-war A lot of anti-war things
Speaker 185: Kamala said some sort of Meaningless cliches around Not liking the war in Gaza as well From
The
Speaker 12: podcast bros Just never
Speaker 288: talked about them
They
Speaker 12: were
Speaker 288: audience captured Willfully They liked
it
It was
Speaker 260: commercially very lucrative for them to be on this Trump train thing.
And so why
Speaker 260: would they ever – they wouldn't get – of course they wouldn't give any credence to the idea that you can work with
Kamala, right? It
Speaker 350: doesn't make any
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): sense on their own terms. But I think Trump said far more anti-war things than Kamala did. I disagree.
Speaker 335: Appealed to that base. Did Kamala
Speaker 246: ever go out and give a pre-prepared speech threatening that –
Speaker 246: Number one, she's concluded that Iran is trying to assassinate her, and therefore the entire country can be blown to smithereens. Because Trump did that, and sure enough, he is now blowing Iran to smithereens. And when was that again?
That was
Speaker 246: September of 2024.
Right before
Speaker 351: the election. Right.
Yeah. I don't
Speaker 344: remember Dave Smith commenting on that, or Tucker, or all these other people. Okay, that's fair,
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): but did Kamala do anything like what Trump did in Michigan? Yeah.
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): that that campaigning that we just
Speaker 352: uh yeah she did
Speaker 260: stuff i mean like let me look the democratic party well the democratic nomination that in 2024 was a shambles right so they you
Speaker 246: know they did stuff where like they wouldn't even allow a palestinian to speak at the convention um i covered that in the at the convention um
But
Speaker 246: yeah, I mean, they, they, they tried, I mean, I don't, I don't have a specific example, but I'd be almost positive. I could
Speaker 291: find examples if I Googled for 30 seconds right now of Kamala and her surrogates kind of like doing these sort of placating things with a Muslim or Arab constituency. Sure.
Speaker 309: Right.
Speaker 15 (lower-pitched voice): But, but again, we like the fact that you would have, that you're, you're almost certain, whereas we're, we're
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): definitely certain that Trump did that. Like it suggests that Trump did campaign more on anti-war than Kamala
Speaker 315: did.
I just
Speaker 315: disagree. You don't think Trump campaigned more on anti-war than
Speaker 353: common law? No, I think he had
Speaker 271: much more effective propagandists that created that impression for people, including yourself, it seems, such as Tulsi
Speaker 277: Gabbard and RFK Jr. and Tucker and Joe Rogan and Theo Vaughn and J.D. Vance, et cetera. They got together to create
Speaker 355: that impression, which was politically clever.
on
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): the substance, on the merits, no I understand your point on that we're not even talking about policy right now, we're just talking about campaigning if you were to compare anti-war statements from Kamala vs. Trump in the 2024 campaign trail
my guess
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): is that Trump would likely have far more anti-war statements than Kamala, obviously we
Speaker 315: don't have an answer to that
right
Speaker 246: now, I mean some of that was just a function of Kamala being in the incumbent administration, so what's she going to make anti-war statements about the Biden-Harris foreign policy record?
she's
Speaker 203: gonna credit she's gonna denounce her own record probably not just like you know and you know trump ran three times for president people always forget 2020 did trump go around denouncing making anti-war statements in 2020 when he was in power along with
my
Speaker 345: pets i don't really recall many every now and then he'll say something like oh we're against the military industrial complex or something which is like a total joke i mean they're an absolute bonanza whenever he's in office yeah um
Speaker 345: But no, I just don't think...
I
Speaker 319: think a lot of that was a confected narrative. Again, politically brilliant. Look, he won the election.
Speaker 356: Yeah.
It was
Speaker 319: very effective, appealing to a certain demographic of like anti-establishment podcast listening guys. Really?
That's a
Speaker 319: big constituency.
Speaker 297: Yeah. And they
Speaker 319: got the same impression oftentimes that you're describing. And why did they get it? Because of this surrogate
Speaker 345: movement,
Speaker 345: of you know tucker joe rogan elon musk kelsey gabbard rfk jr spewing nonsense
that yeah i do think there
Speaker 345: needs to be still be some kind of account accounting for just like i thought the same in 2016 when there was also a seismic media failure although it was more concentrated in the quote-unquote mainstream media but by 2024 we have an ascendant alternative media or independent media for how we define the ecosystem who are even worse in a lot of a lot of ways, amazingly enough, then
the truth
Speaker 345: traditional media, in terms of the false information, false political information they were transmitting
Speaker 203: out to the public and profiting from.
Speaker 322: We're at
Speaker 203: war with Iran
Speaker 359: right now. Hello? Am I crazy? I
Speaker 358: understand what you're saying, although
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): there is I think you would acknowledge there's at least credit we can give to the podcast guys for holding him accountable and being like, hey, we oppose this. What the hell? Dave Smith, Tucker, Rogan,
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): they've they've very strongly i know you have different feelings about tucker but like rogan and dave smith have very strongly uh joe rogan
Speaker 11: had donald trump on the basically the eve of the presidential election in his studio for three
hours he could have asked him
Speaker 12: about iran actually trump brought up iran on his own accord and said look things
Speaker 291: are dangerous for a president
you know
Speaker 360: meaning
Speaker 291: alluding to him potentially being assassinated by iran
Joe
Speaker 271: Rogan didn't ask any follow-up questions on that oh I know he's
not a
Speaker 271: journalist he's just a comedian bro okay well if like you're now this Johnny Carson figure where you're getting presidential candidates on the eve of the general election to make pilgrimage to you and you know jockey for your endorsement
I don't know
Speaker 12: maybe you should up your game a little bit but it was an ass kiss fest because Joe Rogan says oh we've been betrayed now he's been betrayed because he's clueless did
he know
Speaker 12: about the
Speaker 12: bombed the smithereens clip or about endorsing joint u.s israeli strikes on nuclear facilities
did he
Speaker 12: know anything about the first term record did he know about
the
Speaker 11: personnel all the stuff i've been talking about ad nauseum on this podcast probably not so no i don't give joe rogan credit i give joe rogan i i find i find him almost i find him foolish but no for for for
for
Speaker 11: for
Speaker 271: contributing to the propagandistic misconceptions that now have led some people to believe that they've been betrayed by something that could not have been more eminently foreseeable
Speaker 12: and telegraphed. I wrote a whole thing last June, this Trump after Trump bombed around the first time. Trump bombs around this possibly the most telegraphed event in human history. And I go through mountains of information demonstrating that, okay?
Speaker 12: so no
Speaker 260: dave smith doesn't get credit no but they're all dave smith dave smith first of all i'm not crediting
Speaker 361: dave smith for anything anymore but they're a little bit
of a
Speaker 361: personal vendetta because they're criticizing podcast which i'm
Speaker 12: supposed
to be some
Speaker 12: comedy podcast but amazingly i don't think i've ever heard him say a single thing that's funny um comic dave smith and he says it would be justifiable to for me to be murdered
Speaker 12: because he doesn't like my views on the Jeffrey Epstein story. So, no, I'm not going to credit Dave Smith because I think that actually is an insight. I'm sure he was joking. He
was
Speaker 363: not joking. He was dead serious. He was not joking?
No, he
Speaker 363: was dead serious.
And
Speaker 265: he continues to reaffirm that.
He was
Speaker 363: dead serious that you should be killed for your Epstein coverage. He was dead serious that he's he's he he couched it
Speaker 12: and saying, look, I'm not actively calling for anyone to go murder Michael Tracy. However, he says it's totally justifiable and even good and welcome and right for people
Speaker 260: to have the
Speaker 246: reaction to what his position is on Epstein, that they would want to go murder him. That's what he said.
Speaker 246: that's
Speaker 364: your podcast intellectual
Speaker 365: where can I find that clip I posted the clip it was probably like in mid-February
Speaker 324: okay was that on his show yeah it was on whatever
Speaker 308: dopey show he's got some podcast I would like
Speaker 65 (lower-pitched voice): to find that and review that for myself before commenting you think I'm
Speaker 366: mischaracterizing it I just want to see what
Speaker 365: go search for me put my username on x and just go comment Dave Smith It's like from February
i don't know 19th or
Speaker 367: something listen he's he's he's a good friend of mine i like him so if listen he's a piece
Speaker 18 (lower-pitched voice): of shit if if what you're saying is right i i will i will send this to him and i'll ask him i'll be like hey what's what the hell's going on here he's a piece of shit but if if i feel like he's joking then i'll come back to you but it's not he wasn't joking if okay if he was serious i will i will ask and
Speaker 278 (lower-pitched voice): then and then on x a couple of times because i posted the clip and he doubled down on it pretty
much
okay i
Speaker 368: will watch the clip and then i will i
Speaker 271: mean he's gonna try to say oh i wasn't calling for anyone what he says was i wasn't calling for you to be murdered
Speaker 246: you're lying i'm saying i know that you couched it by saying look i'm not actively calling for anyone to murder you i'm just saying it
would be
Speaker 246: defensible for somebody to
Speaker 291: think that they ought to murder you based on your political views on the jeffrey epstein story that i don't like that's what he said
he's
Speaker 291: a piece of shit he's not funny
Speaker 306: um all right I mean comic Dave Smith I mean have you ever laughed at a single thing he's ever said seriously be
Speaker 58 (lower-pitched voice): honest I I've only really seen his political commentary not his
Speaker 306: right so the
answer is
Speaker 306: no even though he's supposed to he's
Speaker 266: supposed
Speaker 58 (lower-pitched voice): to be a comedian he's one on YouTube but I like Tim
Speaker 266: Dillon does political commentary as well but he's actually funny
dave smith i
Speaker 266: don't know what he is and he's just like
Speaker 308: this you have this scourge of failed of like not unfunny comedians who then transition to like political prognosticators to
Speaker 14: be fair you probably also haven't seen one of his specials either because he does political
Speaker 369: i tried to watch some of
it actually
Speaker 369: with richard hanania with donald lark and it wasn't funny
Speaker 14: okay okay
well
Speaker 58 (lower-pitched voice): listen i think we've fully exhausted this i do okay i i do i do have some more points on the the your criticism of rogan and the podcast stuff but we'll get
Speaker 370: another time we'll go into it
yeah yeah
Speaker 58 (lower-pitched voice): yeah i feel like we fully
when
Speaker 370: are you gonna when is this gonna be posted exhausted
Speaker 31: um because i i just i debated senator ron johnson today about the iran war and that did you debate
him
Speaker 371: or interview
him both
Speaker 31: critically interview and ask very
Speaker 358: tough questions and i think i'll
take a
Speaker 358: look at
it um that will
Speaker 358: how do you how do
Speaker 373: you arrange that just ask him
Speaker 358: Uh, yeah. Yeah. Um,
Speaker 373: he, well, he, he did some good work a few
Speaker 374: times.
Speaker 358: Yeah. He did
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): some good work, uh, revealing, um, uh, he examined some recent, uh, Biden era COVID documents about them
Speaker 31: downplaying vaccine side effects. So I actually, I reached out about that. Um, so, and then he, his team said yes to that. And then I said, and they asked, do you want to ask about anything else? And then I said, yeah, Iran war. And they said, sure. So,
Speaker 31: i'm i'm not i'm sure whenever it comes out yeah just let me know in any case uh the ron johnson debate will be out friday uh april 3rd and i think because that's tied to the news we didn't really talk about anything tied to the news today so uh we talked more about
Speaker 376: war is not tied to the
news
Speaker 14: no no but like the like
Speaker 31: what's happened in the last 12 hours whereas with ron johnson we did um so this will be out uh probably uh monday tuesday next week
Speaker 31: okay and we'll and we'll talk more about podcast stuff um that you went into in the last few minutes there
Speaker 377: that i won't get a chance to respond to now because it's just it's been a while here this is my second podcast okay yeah this is a
Speaker 378: long day for you yeah all right i i mean i just spent i spent the early part of the day at a epstein uh settlement hearing for okay we get into
it all
Speaker 379: right interesting okay uh talk to you later